{
  "understanding-banking" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Acknowledge that you have never worked in the field of finance before but you have done the research and talked to professionals in the industry. Bankers help companies with transactions: buying and selling companies or raising capital. The day-to-day jobs include preparing presentations, financial analysis and marketing material such as Executive Summaries.",
      "question" : "Question 1: You’ve never worked in finance before. How much do you know about what bankers actually do?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "Make it clear that you've done your homework and you understand it's going to be an 80-100 hour per week job. Perhaps give an example of a period of time where you had to work that much and how you dealt with it.",
      "question" : "Question 2: How much do you know about the lifestyle in this industry? Do you know how many hours you’re going to work each week?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "1) Meet with the client and gather basic information: company financials, industry overview and who their customers are. 2) Meet with other bankers and lawyers to draft the S-1 registration statement: describes company business and markets it to investors. 3) Receive feedback from SEC and keep revising document until satisfaction. 4) Road trip: spend time convincing institutional investors to invest and once capital is raised, the company starts trading on an exchange.",
      "question" : "Question 3: Let’s say I’m working on an IPO for a client. Can you describe briefly what I would do?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "Emphasize that you have experience working long hours and not just within a short time frame but over a period of time. Because of how this question is framed, you might want to talk about a time OUTSIDE of your extracurriculars.",
      "question" : "Question 4: I see you were an English major in college, and had time to participate in a lot of different activities. Can you talk about a time when you had to work long hours and make sacrifices?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Depends on the deal but most common structure: 1) Bank credentials (prove their expertise) 2) Summary of company's options 3) Valuation and appropriate financial models 4) Potential acquisition targets (buy-side) or potential buyers (sell-side) 5) Summary/conclusion and key recommendations",
      "question" : "Question 5: What’s in a pitch book?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "This is bank-dependant and will differ for boutiques, middle-market firms and bulge brackets so you need to research prior to your interview. Typical product groups include: Mergers and Acquisitions, Leveraged Finance, Restructuring and possibly Equity Capital Markets and Debt Capital Markets. Common industry groups include Healthcare, Retail, Energy, Natural Resources, Technology, Media, Telecom (TMT), Real Estate. Most bulge brackets do not have restructuring groups, it's more for middle and boutique firms. ",
      "question" : "Question 6: Can you tell me about the different product and industry groups at our bank?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "Usually based on relationships. Banks develop relationships with companies years before they need anything and when it comes time to deal, the company calls the different banks it has spoken with and asks them to pitch for the business. This is called a 'bake off' and the company selects a winner after.",
      "question" : "Question 7: How do companies select the bankers they work with?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "1) Meet with company, create initial marketing like the Executive Summary and Offering Memorandum(OM) and decide on potential buyers 2) Send out ES to potential buyers to gauge interest 3) Send NDAs to interested buyers with more detailed information 4) Set a 'bid deadline' and solicit written Indication of Interest (IOIs) from buyers 5) Select which buyers to advance to the next round 6) Continue responding to requests and setting up due diligence 7) Set another bid deadline and pick winner 8) Negotiate terms of the Purchase Agreements with the winner and announce the deal",
      "question" : "Question 8: Walk me through the process of a typical sell-side M&A deal."
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "1) Spend a lot of time doing research on dozens or hundreds of potential acquisition targets, go through multiple cycles of selection and filtering with the company you're representing 2) Narrow down the list based on feedback and decide on which ones to approach 3) Conduct meetings and gauge the receptivity of each potential seller 4) As discussions become more serious, conduct more in-depth due diligence and figure out your offer price 5) Negotiate the price and the key terms of the Purchase Agreement and then announce the transaction",
      "question" : "Question 9: Walk me through the process of a typical buy-side M&A deal."
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "Similar to the IPO process but fewer banks are involved, don't need SEC approval (debt is not sold to the general public): 1) meet with the client and gather basic information: financials, industry, customers 2) Work closely with DCM/Leveraged Finance to develop debt financing or an LBO model for the company and figure out what kind of leverage, coverage ratios and covenants might be appropriate 3) Create an investor memorandum describing all of this 4) Go out to potential debt investors and win commitments from them to finance the deal",
      "question" : "Question 10: Walk me through a debt issuance deal."
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "ECM, DCM are both markets-based than M&A. In M&A, your job is to execute buy-side, sell-side transactions whereas ECM, DCM is staying on top of the market, following current trends and making recommendations to industry and product groups for clients and pitch books.",
      "question" : "Question 11: How are Equity Capital Markets (ECM) and Debt Capital Markets (DCM) different from M&A or industry groups?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "They're similar but Leveraged Finance is more 'modelling intensive' and does more of the deal execution with industry and M&A groups on LBOs and debt financings. DCM, by contrast, is more closely tied to the markets and tracks trends and relevant data.",
      "question" : "Question 12: What’s the difference between DCM and Leveraged Finance?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "It's when a company (public or private) decides to sell of a specific division rather than sell the entire company. Very similar to sell-side M&A but messier because you're dealing with part of a company rather than the whole thing. Need to create a 'standalone operating model' for that particular division and is very important, transaction structure and valuation are more complex.",
      "question" : "Question 13: Explain what a divestiture is."
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "Put the company name in the header. Divide the slide into 4 equal parts. Top left describes the business, headquarters and key executives. Top right contains a stock chart, historical and projected financial metrics and multiples. Bottom left contains the company's products and services. Bottom right should have key geographies with a color-coded map.",
      "question" : "Question 14: Imagine you want to draft a 1-slide company profile for an investor. What would you put there?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "At a high-level, you want to see what their expansion goals are and how they can best achieve them - whether it's by partnering with another company, expanding with M&A or expanding organically with new products and services. As an IBanker, you could provide value by making introductions to potential M&A targets and partners, advise on the best negotiation strategy, what companies would be most receptive, what type of price to expect and how to manage the entire process.",
      "question" : "Question 15: Let’s say you’re hired as the financial advisor for a company. What value could you add for them if they ask you about their suggested growth / M&A strategy?"
    }
  },
  "warren-buffett" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Always ask for the investor's goals first!! Are they looking for capital gains over 30-40 years: well diversified portfolio is probably best? Are they looking for tax-free retirement income: municipal bonds would be good? What types of assets interest them?",
      "question" : "Question 1: Let’s say you had $10 million to invest in anything. What would you do with it?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "1) Price 2) Form of payment: cash, debt, equity 3) Future plans for the company compared to your own plans; There are so many factors that could be listed but these are the key ones. You can also point out that if something particularly important to you like retaining a role in the company, then a difference of intentions there could be a deal-breaker.",
      "question" : "Question 2: If you owned a small business and were approached by a larger company about an acquisition, how would you think about the offer, and how would you make a decision on what to do?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Do research beforehand to be able to speak about trends in that market. 3 mistakes most interviewees make: 1) describing something that is not recent or relevant ex. 'talk about how companies are shifting their software to the Internet' 2) don't explain the 'why' ex. 'they're shifting to the web because it's cheaper and lower maintenance for them' 3) they don't explain the impact on the market as a whole ex. 'such companies are growing very quickly while more traditional companies are either struggling or shifting to that model'",
      "question" : "Question 3: We do most of our work with technology companies. Can you talk about a trend or company in the industry that has piqued your interest lately?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "Ask follow up questions to see if the interviewer is looking for something more specific. If no further direction is provided, then you would say you'd think about some type of niche business with high margins that requires little startup capital ($1 million is not a lot) and ongoing maintenance - those make it harder to turn a profit and sell that business one day. This is one reason why some PE investors focus on software companies. It's better to focus on a niche market because most broad, horizontal markets are already dominated by major companies. Explain your reasoning on why this type of business would be attractive and how it could grow with minimal future investment.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Let’s say you could start any type of business you wanted, and you had $1 million in initial funds. What would you do?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Do not say something commonly known like Google or Apple. Instead, go more obscure and pick a company no one knows so that they can tell you've done your research so that they're less likely to ask probing questions. You don't necessarily need to give financial details, but if the company is public you can easily find the information. When you talk, make the firm attractive and emphasize qualities that investors would find appealing, such as a well-diversified customer base, a unique competitive advantage in the market or a high-margin business model.",
      "question" : "Question 5: Can you talk about a company you admire and what makes them attractive to you?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "To assess whether it is viable or not, you must determine whether you can make a profit. For a laundry machine operation, you'd start by looking at the location, estimate how many customers you could get, how frequently they do laundry and how much they pay each time to do their laundry. These figures give you an idea of monthly/annual revenue. On the expenses side, biggest cost would be the upfront construction and/or purchase of the build and machines. You would probably need a loan for this. Then take into account the cost of maintaing and servicing the machines, building maintenance and employee wages. Location is the biggest role in the success of this type of business. If this company was next to an apartment complex where everyone has laundry machines, you're doomed from the beginning.",
      "question" : "Question 6: Let’s assume you are going to start a laundry machine business. How would you analyze whether it’s viable?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "You want to say who the buyer and seller were - include background information on the companies - as well as the price and the multiples if they are readily available. Read the relevant Wall Street Journal article on it, and discuss the dynamics of the deal - how it developed, if anyone else was interested, and what implications it has on the industry.",
      "question" : "Question 7: Tell me about an M&A deal that interested you recently."
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "Similar to talking about a company you admire. One key difference is that you need to mention specific financial figures. Since the company is public, it shouldn't be too hard to find. Look at Revenue, EBITDA and P/E multiples and saying whether it is higher or lower than competitors is a step in the right direction. Struture: 1) Give the name and summarize what they do 2) Brief overview of its financials 3) State how it is undervalued or more attractive than rivals due to competitive advantages 4) Say how there is a long-term trend in its favor 5) Talk about how good the next 5-10 years will be for the company.",
      "question" : "Question 8: Pitch me a stock."
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "Banks made mortgage loans to people who were in no position to pay them off or even meet monthly payments. Borrowing was easy because interest rates were at historical lows. At the same time, these mortgage loans were combined and packaged into securities that banks traded, acquired and sold to investors. A typical package might contain mortgages given to credible borrowers as well as risky borrowers, more risky ones were labelled as subprime. The thinking was that even if one defaulted, the rest still had value. As unqualified borrowers defaulted, buyers disappeared overnight and the value of these assets plummeted to $0. As a result, the value of many of these banks approached $0 and went bankrupt - all because these securities were so complex nobody understood their real value and the risks involved.",
      "question" : "Question 9: Can you explain to me, in simple terms, the subprime crisis?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "Give an answer and back it up with solid reasoning. These days, it's probably better to say yes because as we witnessed with teh Lehman Brothers, if a financial institution that's large enough collapses, it can have ripple effects and bring down the rest of the economy and financial markets with it.",
      "question" : "Question 10: Do you agree with the $700 billion bank bailout?"
    }
  },
  "why-banking" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Talk about how banking is about what skills you bring to the table and what kind of person you are rather than how many internships you've had. Discuss how you've worked long hours/in teams/paid attention to details before and succeeded at whatever you've done before. You can also point out that although someone might have had a banking internship, that doesn't mean he/she did well in it - and that you may be better equipped with your experiences.",
      "question" : "Question 1: I see you have no relevant finance experience – why should we hire you over someone who’s had a previous banking internship?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "You want to understand the bigger picture and how and why large companies make decisions rather than just working with individual investors. Working on transactions and making an impact is more interesting to you than giving individual advice to high net worth individuals (or institutions).",
      "question" : "Question 2: I see you’ve worked mostly in wealth management before – why are you looking to switch into banking now?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Talk about your long-term view and how a downturn could be an even better time to enter the industry because you'll know how to work when times are both good and bad. In addition, you've been interested in finance for a long time and that you're not going to let short-term difficulties deter you from entering the field - you've explored other options and concluded that this is the best one for you.",
      "question" : "Question 3: You’re a smart guy/girl with a lot of options, and right now the economy is not doing well and lots of banks have failed. Why are you still interested in banking when you could do anything else?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "Reverse of question 3, you can apply a similar strategy and say how you hold a long-term view and haven't just become interested overnight. Being able to point out specific evidence to back up your interest - your own portfolio, the finance/business clubs you're in, or even day trading - also helps.",
      "question" : "Question 4: The economy has been improving lately, and more people are “getting interested” in finance. How do I know you’re serious and not just following everyone else?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Almost anything could work here but make sure it's nothing too recent. Otherwise, it looks like you became interested on a whim. Be sure to explain how your initial interest led you into the internships, activities, jobs you pursued and how those have led you to where you are today.",
      "question" : "Question 5: Where did your interest in finance begin?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "You're looking for something faster-paced where there's a better learning opportunity and more of a chance to make an impact. You've been interested all along and now you realize you reall ywant to do it after exploring other alternatives and not liked them. If this is a small company to a big company (or vice versa) you can also say something about that, using the standard reasons we went through before - small means more responsibility and client interaction , and big means working on more major deals and learning more technical skills.",
      "question" : "Question 6: If you enjoyed your last internship and got an offer to come back, why are you trying to switch into investment banking now?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "This is the key question asked of many career changers and anyone else at the VP-level (or above) at a company who is looking to switch into banking as an Associate. Here are the main points to emphasize: 1) You've done your homework and spoken with a lot of people about this move - and you like the finance work you've done before 2) Banking is faster-paced and appeals to you more because you make more of an impact 3) You're fine with the pay cut and additional hours because of the improved opportunities to make an impact and advance.",
      "question" : "Question 7: You’ve advanced into a high-paying position at your current company – why would you want to move here, take a pay cut, and work twice the hours?"
    }
  },
  "failure" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Do NOT give an actual fear (losing your friends, hating your life, getting laid off, working too much etc...). Instead, it's better to go with something innocuous like 'Doing a lot of deals and not always getting to see them through to the conclusion because anything could cause a large trasnaction to collapse' or having concerns about the deal flow if the market is poor.",
      "question" : "Question 1: What’s your greatest fear about investment banking?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "You will do something finance - related in a field like corporate finance/strategy or maybe something else at a financial firm.'If I have absolutely no way to get into banking at your firm this year, then I’d go work in the Valuations group at one of the Big 4 firms where I already have an offer – or to the 2 boutiques that keep inviting me in for interviews.' ",
      "question" : "Question 2: What’s your “Plan B” if you can’t get into investment banking this year?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Bankers hire people who are 1) smart 2) can do the work 3) are likeable; In addition to meeting all those criteria, you've also done well in the real world and have stellar recommendations to back you up - plus, since you don't come from a blue chip background, you're more motivated to succeed than the Harvard guy. 'He does have impressive credentials. But at a bank, you want someone who’s smart, can do the work, and is easy to get along with. I’ve done well in school and am working on an Honors Thesis right now, and I have great recommendations from my 2 previous bosses in my Sales & Trading internships. And I spend most of my free time sky diving and going on adventures in different countries. So while he may be qualified on paper, in banking it all comes down to real-world experience and what kind of camaraderie you have with everyone. I’m confident that I excel in both of those areas – and since I’m not from a privileged background, I’m even more motivated to succeed than someone who is.'",      "question" : "Question 3: That guy over there has a 4.0 from Wharton/Harvard – why should I hire you over him, given that you’re much less impressive?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "No - unless it comes up during the meeting, in which case you speak only if the MD ask you about it. In that case, you should just briefly acknowledge it then move to a different topic. It's bad if you make a mistake like that but it's worse if you embarrass your MD by pointing it out in broad daylight - chances are that no one will notice it anyways since pitch books are rarely read in meetings.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Let’s say your MD is meeting with a client and you have been invited. As he’s presenting, you notice a mistake in the materials – do you point it out?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "The key here is to spin whatever you've done in a positive light. Don't say you were out of work/laid off/looking for work at the time - just mention that briefly and say you were also doing something constructive with your time such as education, travel, volunteering, or a respectable hobby. If you’ve had some other type of gap because of school, economic hardship, or something similar, you need to find the strength in whatever weakness you had – this is really just a disguised 'weakness' question. 'The truth is, my family went through some financial hardships back then and I was forced to take a leave of absence from school for awhile, and spend most of my time working to help them pay the bills. Initially I was pretty upset, but I learned a lot about time management, work ethic, and how to juggle 5 different major responsibilities at once. I lost some time on my peers, but I came out more motivated than before, helped my family get back on their feet, and got started with independent study to help myself catch up.'",
      "question" : "Question 5: I see you have a big gap in your work experience over the past few months / few years / I see you have a gap of 2-3 years a few years ago – what happened there?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "Don't even try to make up an excuse unless it's a REALLY good one (e.g. both your parents passed away that semester) - just admit it then point out what you've learned and how you've improved sinec then. Maybe you took it upon yourself to do additional self-study - or you changed your approach to studying and did much better in subsequent Accounting classes.",
      "question" : "Question 6: hy did you get a C in accounting? (Or other bad grade in highly relevant class)"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "For this one it sounds like you’re making an excuse if you say something like, 'The market was bad' or 'They didn’t give out any offers' – even if both of those are true. It's a better bet to say something like, 'I did well in my internship and got positie reviews, but I didn't fit in with the group's culture. From those I've spoken with so far at your firm, I think this is a much better for me.' It's hard to argue with doing the work but just not fitting in with the group.",
      "question" : "Question 7: Why did you NOT receive a return offer from your internship?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "For this one, if it’s a bank you have NOT interviewed with before it’s best to say you haven’t participated in recruiting so they don’t see you as 'damaged goods.' But if you’re on the record as having interviewed there before, you need to admit the truth. Again, you want to make your time seem well spent and productive: independant study/additional research and am now more focused than ever on banking.",
      "question" : "Question 8: You graduated last year and don’t have anything listed on your resume since then – what have you been doing, and did you participate in recruiting last year?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "Even if you really do prefer New York or London, you can’t say this in an interview with a regional office because your #1 goal has to be getting AN offer – not getting the perfect offer in the perfect location. It’s best to say something like, 'I realize it is unusual and that are other places are sometimes more popular, but I’m most interested in [Location] because it’s the best place for [Industry You Like], I have a lot of friends and family here, and on top of all that the cost of living also beats New York.' This way you acknowledge their concerns upfront but also point out solid reasons for picking this location.",
      "question" : "Question 9: Why are we your first choice? Wouldn’t you like London or New York more?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "'I realize I don’t fit the typical profile of someone applying to banking – but that also comes with some advantages. I’ve been around longer and explored different industries, so I have a better of what I want, and I’m going to be more committed than someone just out of school. I’ve also had a lot more leadership experience and understand how to get things done in a large company – and I’ve climbed up steep learning curves plenty of times over the years.'",
      "question" : "Question 10: Why are you so old? (Stated more tactfully)"
    }
  },
  "outside-the-box" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Some interviewees take this as a cue to tie your choice back to being a team player, hard worker, or such but that’s not the best approach. For “creativity”-type questions, interviewers want you to be... creative. So think about your real personality and say something that matches that.",
      "question" : "Question 1: What type of animal / vegetable would you be?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "With this type of question you can show more 'banker-like' traits such as ambition and hard work – but you shouldn’t take it too seriously. So maybe the headline states that you climbed Mt. Everest, sold your company in an IPO, or became a best-selling author – you want 'ambition + creativity / coolness' for this type of question.",
      "question" : "Question 2: Let’s say that in the future your name turns up as the front page headline of a newspaper one day – what would the story be about?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Q: What was the best part of Playboy's IPO? A: The pitch book Q: Why don't sharks attack bankers? A: Professional Courtesy Q:I went to the zoo the other day, there was only one dog in it, it was a shitzu.",
      "question" : "Question 3: Tell me a joke."
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "Beta in the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) measures expected return and expected risk. Higher Beta means a higher potential return, but also more risk. You probably want to say above 1.0, but not too much above it – you’re much more ambitious than the average person, which causes you to try lots of new things and achieve quite a bit, so that inevitably carries some risk. Bankers like to think of themselves as 'entrepreneurial' even though banking is extremely different from entrepreneurship, so you should take advantage of this line of thinking and indulge them.",
      "question" : "Question 4: What’s your personal Beta?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Don’t say 'cocaine' or any other drug / porn-like / illegal activity (this should be common sense but you wouldn’t believe the emails I get). Try to discuss an internship or job experience you had that you never expected to get, or some type of extracurricular/leadership experience that was somewhat random and turned out to be great – and talk about how it was a calculated risk and that you got a lot out of the decision you made.",
      "question" : "Question 5: What’s the riskiest thing you’ve ever done?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "Don’t say, 'I would start my own business...' or 'I would invest it in...' – many people completely ignore the actual question here. It’s best to tie this back to whatever your interests and passions are – so you might use the money to support volunteer work you’ve done, extended travel that you’ve always wanted to take, or maybe even to buy that race car you’ve always wanted. Just make sure your answer is believable – if you have never worked at a non-profit or in a volunteer group in your life, don’t suddenly try to be a saint. If you love cars, say you would think about buying a car you’ve always wanted... among other things.",
      "question" : "Question 6: Let’s say that you have $1 million, but you are NOT allowed to invest it or otherwise use it to create more money. What would you spend the capital on instead?"
    }
  },
  "restruct-distress" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Restructuring bankers advise distressed comapnies - businesses going bankrupt, in the middle of a bankruptcy or getting out of a bankruptcy - and help them change their capital structure to get out of bankruptcy, avoid it in the first place, or assist with a sale of the company depending on the scenario.",
      "question" : "Question 1: How much do you know about what you actually do in Restructuring?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "There is the debtor (the company itself) or the creditors (anyone that has lent the company money). It's similar to sell-side and buy-side M&A - in one you're advising the company who's trying to sell or get out of the mess they are in and in the other you are advising buyers and lenders that are trying to take what they can from the company. Note that 'creditors' are often multiple parties since it's anyone who's loaned the company money. You need to research which bank does what, but typically Blackstone and Lazard advise the debtor and Hokey advises the creditor (these 3 are commonly known as the top 3 in the field).",
      "question" : "Question 2: What are the 2 different “sides” of a Restructuring deal? Do you know which one we usually advise?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "You gain a very specialized skill set (and therefore become more valuable/employable) and much of the work is actually more technical/interesting than M&A, for example. You are get more exposure because you get to see both the bright sides and the not-so-bright sides of companies. If you're coming in with any legal background or have aspirations of doing that in the future, there's a ton of overlap with Restructuring because you have to operate within a legal framework and attorneys are involved at every step of the process - so that can be one of your selling points as well.",
      "question" : "Question 3: Why are you interested in Restructuring besides the fact that it’s a “hot” area currently?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "See question 3 about the legal and 'better technical skills'. You can also use the experience to work at a Distressed Investments or Special Situations Fund, which most people outside of Restructuring don't have access to. Or you could just go back to M&A or normal investing too, and still have superior technical knowledge to other bankers.",
      "question" : "Question 4: How are you going to use your experience in Restructuring for your future career goals?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "More so than M&A and IPO processes, Restructuring/Distressed M&A requires extremely specialized knowledge and relationships. There are only a few banks with good practices, and they are selected on the basis of their experience during similar deals in the industry as well as their relationships with all the other parties that will be involved in the deal process. Remember that a Restructuring involves many more parties than a normal M&A or financing deals does - there are lawyers, shareholders, debt investors, suppliers, directors, management, and crisis managers, and managing everyone can be like herding cats. Lawyers can also be a major source of business, since they're heavily involved with any sort of Restructuring/Distress scenario.",
      "question" : "Question 5: How would a distressed company select its Restructuring bankers?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "1) Company cannot meet its debt obligations/interest payments 2) Creditors accelerate debt payments and force the company into bankruptcy 3) Acquisition has gone poorly or a company has just written down the value of its assets steeply and needs extra capital to stay afloat 4) There is a liquidity crunch and the company cannot afford to pay its vendors or suppliers",
      "question" : "Question 6: Why would company go bankrupt in the first place?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "1) Refinance and obtain fresh debt/equity 2) Sell the company (either as a whole or divestiture) 3) Restructure its financial obligations to lower interest payments/debt repayments or issue debt with PIK interest to reduce the cash interest expense 4) File for bankruptcy and use that opportunity to obtain additional financing, restructure its obligations and be free of onerous contracts",
      "question" : "Question 7: What options are available to a distressed company that can't meet debt obligations?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "1) Refinance: Least disruptive to company and would revive confidence, difficult to attract investors to a company on the verge of going bankrupt 2) Sale: Shareholders could get some value and creditors would be less infuriated knowing that funds are coming, unlikely to obtain a good valuation in a distressed sale so it would sell for a fraction of its worth 3) Restructuring: could resolve problems quickly without third party involvement, lenders are often reluctant to increase their exposure to the company and management/lender usually don't see eye-to-eye 4) Bankruptcy: could be the best way to negotiate with lenders, reduce obligations and get additional financing, significant business disruptions and lack of confidence from customers and equity investors would likely lose all their money",
      "question" : "Question 8: What are the advantages and disadvantages of each option for a distressed company?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "These mirror the options that are available to the company itself in a distressed situation: 1) Lend additional capital/grant equity to company 2) Conditional Finance - only agree to invest if the company meets certain crieria like cutting expense, stop losing money, agrees to other terms and covenants 3) Sale - Force the company to hire an investment bank to sell itself or parts of itself 4) Foreclosure - Bank seizes collatoral and forces a bankruptcy filing ",
      "question" : "Question 9: From the perspective of the creditors, what different strategies do they have available to recover their capital in a distressed situation?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "They are more complex, involve more parties, require more specialized/technical skills and have to follow the Bankruptcy legal code - unlike most other types of deals bankers work on. The debtor advisor, for example, might have to work with creditors during a forebearance period and then work with lawyers to determine collateral recoveries for each tranche of debt. Also, unlike most standard M&A deals the negotiation extends beyond two 'sides' - it's not just creditors negotiating with the debtors but also the different creditors negotiating with each other.",
      "question" : "Question 10: How are Restructuring deals different from other types of transactions?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "Chapter 7 bankruptcy is known as a 'liquidation bankruptcy' - the company is too far past the point of reorganization and must instead sell off its asset and pay off creditors. Chapter 11 is more of a 'reorganization' - the company doesn't die, but instead changes the terms on its debt and renegotiates everything to lower interest payments and the dollar value of debt repayments.",
      "question" : "Question 11: What’s the difference between Chapter 7 and Chapter 11 bankruptcy?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "It is money borrowed by the distressed company that has repayment priority over all other existing secured/unsecured debt, equity, and other claims, and is considered 'safe' by lenders because it is subject to stricter terms than other forms of financing. Theoretically, this makes it easier for distressed companies to emerge from the bankruptcy prcoess - though some argue that DIP financing is actually harmful on an empirical basis. Some DIP lending firms are known for trying to take over companies at a significant discount due to the huge amount of collateral they have. One reason companies might choose to file for Chapter 11 Bankruptcy is to gain access to DIP financing.",
      "question" : "Question 12: What is debtor-in-possession (DIP) financing and how is it used with distressed companies?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "Here are the most common adjustments: 1) Adjust COGS for higher vendor costs due to lack of trust from supplies 2) Add back non-recurring legal/other professional fees associated with restructuring and/or distressed sale process 3) Add back excess lease expenses (lack of trust) to Operating Income as well as excess salaries (often done so private company owners can save on taxes) 4) Working capital needs to be adjusted for receivables unlikely to turn into cash, overvalued/insufficient inventory and insufficient payables 5) CapEx spending is often off (if it's too high that might be why they're going bankrupt, if it's too low they might be doing that artificially to save money)",
      "question" : "Question 13: How would you adjust the 3 financial statements for a distressed company when you’re doing valuation or modeling work?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "Most of the above would apply to public companies as well but the point about the excess salaries does not hold true - it's much tougher for public companies to manipulate the system like that and pay abnormal salaries.",
      "question" : "Question 14: Would those adjustments differ for public companies vs. private companies?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "The SE goes negative (which is actually not that uncommon and happens all the time in LBOs and when a company is unprofitable). A company's Equity Market Cap (shares outstanding x share price) would remain positive because that can never be negative.",
      "question" : "Question 15: If the market value of a distressed company’s debt is greater than the company’s assets, what happens to its equity?"
    },
    "16" : {
      "answer" : "1) New debtor-in-possession (DIPs) lenders 2) Secured creditors (revolvers and 'bank debt') 3) Unsecured creditors (high-yield bonds) 4) Subordinated debt investors (similar to high-yield bonds) 5) Mezzanine investors (convertibles, convertible preferred stock, preferred stock, PIK) 6) Shareholders (equity investors)",
      "question" : "Question 16: In a bankruptcy, what is the order of claims on a company’s assets?"
    },
    "17" : {
      "answer" : "You'd have to look at the yields of bonds or the spreads of credit default swaps of comparable companies to get a sense of this. You could also just use the current yields on a company's existing debt to estimate this, though it may be difficult if the existing debt is illiquid.",
      "question" : "Question 17: How do you measure the cost of debt for a company if it is too distressed to issue additional debt (i.e. investors won’t buy any debt from them)?"
    },
    "18" : {
      "answer" : "1) Use the same methodologies most of the time (comparable companies, precedent transactions, DCF) 2) Look more at the lower range of the multiple and make the accounting adjustments 3) Use lower projections for a DCF and anything else that needs projections because you assume a turnaround period is required 4) You might pay more attention to Revenue Muliples if the company is EBIT/EBITDA/EPS-negative 5) You also look at a liquidation valuation under the assumption that the company's assets will be sold off and used to pay its obligations 6) Somtimes you look at valuations on both an assets-only basis and a current liabilities-assumed basis. This distinction exists because you need to make big adjustments to liabilities with distressed companies",
      "question" : "Question 18: How would valuation change for a distressed company?"
    },
    "19" : {
      "answer" : "Even more of the value would come from the terminal value since you normally assume a few years of cash flow-negative turnaround. You might also do a sensitivity table on hitting or missing earnings projections, and also add a premium to WACC to make it higher and account for operating distress.",
      "question" : "Question 19: How would a DCF analysis be different in a distressed scenario?"
    },
    "20" : {
      "answer" : "1) Timing is often quick since the company needs to sell or else they'll go bankrupt 2) Sometimes you'll produce fewer upfront marketing materials (Information Memorandum, Management Presentations etc...) in the interest of speed 3) Creditors often initiate the process rather than the company itself 4) Unlike normal M&A deals, distressed sales can't 'fail' - they result in a sale, a bankrutcy or sometimes a restructuring",
      "question" : "Question 20: Let’s say a distressed company approaches you and wants to hire your bank to sell it in a distressed sale – how would the M&A process be different than it would for a healthy company?"
    },
    "21" : {
      "answer" : "Yes - in a distressed sale, the seller normally has no negotiating leverage because you represent a company that's about to die. The only real way to improve price for your client is to have multiple bidders.",
      "question" : "Question 21: Normally in a sell-side M&A process, you always want to have multiple bidders to increase competition. Is there any reason they’d be especially important in a distressed sale?"
    },
    "22" : {
      "answer" : "In a stock purchase, you acquire 100% of a company's shares as well as all its assets and liabilities (on and off balance sheet). In an asset purchase, you acquire only certain assets of a company and assume only certain liabilities - so you can pick and choose exactly what you're getting. Companies typically use asset purchases for divestitures, distressed M&A, and smaller private companies; anything large, public and healthy generally needs to be acquired through a stock purchase. A buyer almost always prefers an asset purchase so it can avoid assumption of unknown liabilities (there are also tax advantages for the buyer). A distressed seller almost always prefers a stock purchase so it can be rid of all its liabilities and because it gets taxed more heavily when selling assets vs. selling the entire business.",
      "question" : "Question 22: The 2 basic ways you can buy a company are through a stock purchase and an asset purchase. What’s the difference, and what would a buyer in a distressed sale prefer? What about the seller?"
    },
    "23" : {
      "answer" : "Other possible outcomes: 1) Foreclose (either official or unofficial) 2) General assignment (faster alternative to bankruptcy) 3) Section 363 asset sale (a faster, less risky version of a normal asset sale) 4) Chapter 11 bankruptcy 5) Chapter 7 bankruptcy",
      "question" : "Question 23: Sometimes a distressed sale does not end in a conventional stock/asset purchase – what are some other possible outcomes?"
    },
    "24" : {
      "answer" : "This happens even outside of distressed sales - generally the company does it if they want more bids/want to increase competition to drive a higher purchase price.",
      "question" : "Question 24: Normally M&A processes are kept confidential – is there any reason why a distressed company would want to announce the involvement of a banker in a sale process?"
    },
    "25" : {
      "answer" : "Technically, the answer is 'it depends' but practically speaking most of the time the answer is 'no'. If a company is truly distressed, the value of its debts and obligations would most likely exceed the value of its assets - so equity investors rarely get much out of a bankruptcy or distressed sale, especially when it ends in liquidation.",
      "question" : "Question 25: Are shareholders likely to receive any compensation in a distressed sale or bankruptcy?"
    },
    "26" : {
      "answer" : "In a lot of cases, aggressive creditors force this to happen - if they won't agree to the restructuring of its obligations or they can't finalize a sale outside court, they might force a company into a Chapter 11 by accelerating debt payments.",
      "question" : "Question 26: Let’s say a company wants to sell itself or simply restructure its obligations – why might it be forced into a Chapter 11 bankruptcy?"
    },
    "27" : {
      "answer" : "The motivation is simple, use excess balance sheet cash to buy back debt on-the-cheap and sharply reduce interest expense and obligations going forward. It works because the foregone interest on cash is lower than whatever interest rates they pay on their debt - so they reduce their net interest expense no matter what. Companies take this opporunity to rid themselves of excess cash and cancel out their existing debt. Accounting-wise, it's simple: BS cash goes down and debt on the L&SE side goes down by the same amount to make it balance.",
      "question" : "Question 27: Recently, there has been news of distressed companies like GM “buying back” their debt for 50 cents on the dollar. What’s the motivation for doing this and how does it work accounting-wise?"
    },
    "28" : {
      "answer" : "Most likely over-levered companies - ones with too much debt - that were acquired by PE firms in LBOs during the boom years, and now face interest payments they have trouble meeting, along with excess cash.",
      "question" : "Question 28: What kind of companies would most likely enact debt buy-backs?"
    },
    "29" : {
      "answer" : "This happens to low-priority creditors all the time. The capital structure indicates that secured creditors always come first and get first claim to all the proceeds from a sale or series of asset sales; if a creditor is lower on the totem pole, they only get what's left of the proceeds so they have to take a loss on their loans/obligations.",
      "question" : "Question 29: Why might a creditor might have to take a loss on the debt it loaned to a distressed company?"
    },
    "30" : {
      "answer" : "A restructuring does not change the amount of debt outstanding in and of itself - instead, it changes the terms of the debt, such as interest payments, monthly/quarterly principal repayment requirements and the covenants.",
      "question" : "Question 30: What is the end goal of a given financial restructuring?"
    },
    "31" : {
      "answer" : "Restructuring is one possible outcome of a Distressed M&A deal. A company can be 'distressed' for many reasons, but the solution is not always to restructure its debt obligations - it might declare bankruptcy, it might liquidate and sell off its assets, or it might sell 100% of itself to another company. Restructuring just refers to what happens when the distressed company in question decides it wants to change around its debt obligations so that it can better repay them in the future.",
      "question" : "Question 31: What’s the difference between a Distressed M&A deal and a Restructuring deal?"
    },
    "32" : {
      "answer" : "When you acquire the assets of a company, you literally get just the assets. But when you acquire the current liabilities as well, you need to make adjustments to account for the fact that a distressed company's working capital can be extremely skewed. Specifically, 'owed expense' line items like Accounts Payable and Accrued Expenses are often much higher than they would be for a healthy company, so you need to subtract the difference if you're assuming the current liabilities. This results in a deduction to your valuation - so in most cases, the valuation is lower if you're assuming current liabilities.",
      "question" : "Question 32: What’s the difference between acquiring just the assets of a company and acquiring it on a 'current liabilities assumed' basis?"
    },
    "33" : {
      "answer" : "Trick question. MARKET CAP DOES NOT EQUAL SHAREHOLDER'S EQUITY. You might be tempted to say something like, 'SE falls!' but the share price of the company does not affect shareholder's equity, which is a book value. What actually happens: as a result of the share price drop, customers, vendors, suppliers and lendors would be more reluctant to do business with the distressed company - so its revenue might fall and its Accounts Payable and Accrued Expenses might climb to unhealthy levels. All of that might cause the company to fail or require more capital, but the share price decline itself does not lead to bankruptcy. In the case of Bear Stears in 2008, overnight lendors lost confidence as a result of the sudden share price declines and it completely ran out of liquidity as a result - which is a big problem when your business depends on overnight lending.",
      "question" : "Question 33: How could a decline in a company’s share price cause it to go bankrupt?"
    },
    "34" : {
      "answer" : "They rise and the average AP Days might go well beyond what is 'normal' for the industry - this is because a distressed company has trouble paying its vendors and suppliers.",
      "question" : "Question 34: What happens to Accounts Payable Days with a distressed company?"
    },
    "35" : {
      "answer" : "Debt: sometimes if the company is too small or if investors don't believe it has a credible turnaround plan, they will simply refuse to lend it any sort of capital ... Equity: Same as above but worse - since equity investors have a lower priority than debt investors. Plus, for a distressed company to get enough capital, it could mean selling 100% or near 100% of the company due to its depressed market cap.",
      "question" : "Question 35: Let’s say a distressed company wants to raise debt or equity to fix its financial problems rather than selling or declaring bankruptcy. Why might it not be able to do this?"
    },
    "36" : {
      "answer" : "In most cases, it will be higher because you're adjusting for higher-than-normal salaries, one-time legal and restructuring charges, and more.",
      "question" : "Question 36: Will the adjusted EBITDA of a distressed company be higher or lower than the value you would get from its financial statements?"
    },
    "37" : {
      "answer" : "No. In fact, with distressed companies it's really important to analyze cash flows on a debt-free basis precisely because they might have higher-than-normal debt expenses.",
      "question" : "Question 37: Would you use Levered Cash Flow for a distressed company in a DCF since it might be encumbered with debt?"
    },
    "38" : {
      "answer" : "In a Liquidation Valuation you need to adjust the values of the assets to reflect how much you could get if you sold them off separately. You might assume, for example, that you can only recover 50% of the book value of a company's inventory if you tried to sell it off separately. Shareholder's Equity is equal to Assets - Liabilities, but in a Liquidation Valuation we change the values of all the Assets so we can't just use the Shareholder's Equity number.",
      "question" : "Question 38: Let’s say we’re doing a Liquidation Valuation for a distressed company. Why can’t we just use the Shareholders’ Equity number for its value? Isn’t that equal to Assets minus Liabilities?"
    },
    "39" : {
      "answer" : "This varies A LOT by industry, company and the specific assets, but some rough guidelines: 1) Cash: probably close to 100% because it is the most liquid 2) Investments: Varies a lot by what they are and how liquid they are - you might get close to 100% for the ones closest to cash, but significantly less than that for equity investments in other companies 3) Accounts Receivables: Less than what you would get for cash because many customers might just not 'pay' a distressed company 4) Inventory: Less than Cash or AR because inventory is of little use to a different company 5) PP&E: Similar to cash for land and buildings but less than that for equipment 6) Intangible Assets: 0% No one will pay you anything for Goodwill or the value of a brand name - or if they will, it's near impossible to quantify",
      "question" : "Question 39: What kind of recovery can you expect for different assets in a Liquidation Valuation?"
    },
    "40" : {
      "answer" : "The purpose of an LBO model here is not to determine the private equity firm's IRR, but rather to figure out how quickly the company can pay off its debt obligations as well as what kind of IRR any new debt/equity investors can expect. Other than that, it's not much different from the standard LBO model - the mechanics are the same, but you have different kinds of debt, possibly more tranches, and the returns will probably be lower because it's a distressed company, though occasionally 'bargain' deals can turn out to be very profitable. One structural difference is that a distressed company LBO is more likely to take the form of an asset purchase rather than a stock purchase.",
      "question" : "Question 40: How would an LBO model for a distressed company be different?"
    }
  },
  "accounting" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "The 3 major financial statements are: Income Statement, Balance Sheet, Statement of Cash Flows; Income statement gives the company's revenue and expenses, and goes down to Net Income, the final line of the statement. The Balance Sheet shows the company's Assets- its resources - such as Cash, Inventory, PP&E, as well as Liabilities - such as Debt and Accounts Payable - and Shareholder's equity. Assets = Liabilities + SE ... The Cash Flow Statement begins with net income, adjusts for non-cash expenses and working capital changes, and then lists cash flow from Investing and Financing activities, at the end you will see the company's net change in cash.",
      "question" : "Question 1: Walk me through the 3 financial statements."
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "1) Income Statement: Revenue, COGS, Operating Expenses, SG&A, Operating Income, Pretax Income, Net Income 2) Balance Sheet: Cash, Inventory, Accounts Payable, PP&E, Accrued Expenses, Debt, Shareholder's Equity 3) Cash Flow Statements: Net income, Depreciation & Amortization, Stock-Based compensation, Changes in Operating Assets and Liabilities, Cash Flow from Operations, Capital Expenditures, Cash Flow from Investing, Sale/Purchase of Securities/Dividends Issued, Cash Flow from Financing",
      "question" : "Question 2: Can you give examples of major line items on each of the financial statements?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "'To tie the statements together, Net Income from the Income Statement flows into the Shareholder's Equity on the Balance Sheet, and into the top line of the Statement of Cash Flows' Changes to the Balance Sheet items appear as Working Capital changes on the Cash Flow Statemnt, and investing and financing activities affect Balance Sheet items such as PP&E, Debt and Shareholder's Equity. The Cash and Shareholder's Equity items on the Balance Sheet act as 'plugs' with Cash flowing in from the final line on the Cash Flow Statement.",
      "question" : "Question 3: How do the 3 statements link together?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "You would use the Cash Flow Statemnt because it gives a true picture of how much cash the company is generating, independant of all the non-cash expenses you might have. And that's the number #1 thing you care about when analyzing the overall financial health of any business - its cash flow.",
      "question" : "Question 4: If I were stranded on a desert island, only had 1 statement and I wanted to review the overall health of a company – which statement would I use and why?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "You would use the IS and BS because you can create the SCF from both of those, assuming you have before and after versions of the BS that correspond to the same period as IS",
      "question" : "Question 5: Let’s say I could only look at 2 statements to assess a company’s prospects – which 2 would I use and why?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "IS: Operating Income would decline by $10 and assuming a 40% tax rate, Net Income would go down by $6. SFC: Net income at the top goes down by $6, but the $10 depreciation non-cash expense gets added back so overall cash flow from Operations goes UP by $4. There are no changes anywhere else, so the overall net change in Cash goes up by $4. BS: PP&E goes down by $10 on the Assets side because of the Depreciation, and Cash is up $4; Overall, Assets is down by $6. Since Net Income fell by $6 as well, SE is down by $6 and both sides of the Balance Sheet balance. With these questions, go in this order: 1) Income Statement 2) Cash Flow Statement 3) Balance Sheet; Remember that an Asset going up DECREASES your Cash Flow, whereas a Liability going up INCREASES your Cash Flow.",
      "question" : "Question 6: Walk me through how Depreciation going up by $10 would affect the statements."
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "Although depreciation is a non-cash expense, it is tax-deductible. Since taxes are a cash expense, depreciation affects cash by reducing the amount of amount of taxes you pay.",
      "question" : "Question 7: If Depreciation is a non-cash expense, why does it affect the cash balance?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "It could be in a separate line item, or it could be embedded in Cost of Goods Sold or Operating Expenses - every company does it differently. Note that the end result of accounting questions is the same: Depreciation always reduces Pre-Tax Income.",
      "question" : "Question 8: Where does Depreciation usually show up on the Income Statement?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "Confirm that the accrued compensation is now being recognized as an expense (as opposed to just changing non-accrued to accrued compensation). Assuming that's the case Operating Expenses on the IS go up by $10, Pre-Tax income falls by $10 and Net Income falls by $6 (assuming 40% tax rate). On the SCF, Net income is down $6 and Accrued Compensation will increase CF by $10, so overall CF from Operations is up by $4 and the Net Change in Cash at the bottom is up by $4. On the BS, cash is up by $4 which means assets is up by $4. Accrued Compensation is a liability so Liabilities are up by $10 and Retained Earnings are down by $6 due to the Net Income, so both sides balance.",
      "question" : "Question 9: What happens when Accrued Compensation goes up by $10?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "No changes to IS. Inventory is an asset so it decreases your cash flow by $10. That decreases net change in cash flow by $10 so cash is down $10 in the BS but assets is up $10 so it balances out.",
      "question" : "Question 10: What happens when Inventory goes up by $10, assuming you pay for it with cash?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "This is a common interview mistake - incorrectly stating that Working Capital changes show up on the IS. In the case of Inventory, the expense is only recorded when the goods associated with it are sold - so if it' just sitting in a warehouse, it does not cound as a COGS or Operating Expense until the company manufactures it into a product and sells it.",
      "question" : "Question 11: Why is the Income Statement not affected by changes in Inventory?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "At the start of year 1, before anything else has happened, there would be no changes to Apple's Income Statement (yet). On the SCF, the additional investment in factories would show up under CF from Investing as a Net Reduction in CF (so CF is down by $100 so far). And the additional $100 worth of debt raised would increase CF under Financing so they would cancel out. Cash number stays the same. On the BS, there is now an additional $100 of factories in the PP&E line so PP&E is up by $100 and Assets is therefore up by $100. On the other side, debt is up by $100 as well so both sides balance out.",
      "question" : "Question 12: Let’s say Apple is buying $100 worth of new iPod factories with debt. How are all 3 statements affected at the start of “Year 1,” before anything else happens?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "After a year has passed, Apple must pay interest expense and record depreciation. IS: Depreciation expense is $10 and interest expense is $10. Therefore pre-tax is down $20, net income is $12; SCF: Net income is down by $12 but we add back depreciation because it is a non-cash expense. Net change in CF is minus $2; BS: Cash is down by $2, PP&E is down by $10 due to the depreciation, so overall Assets is down by $12. To balance out, SE is down by $12 to balance out. The debt number under Liabilities does not change since we've assumed none of the debt is actually paid back.",
      "question" : "Question 13: Now let’s go out 1 year, to the start of Year 2. Assume the debt is high-yield so no principal is paid off, and assume an interest rate of 10%. Also assume the factories depreciate at a rate of 10% per year. What happens?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "After 2 years, the value of the factories is now $80 if we go with the 10% a year assumption. It is this $80 we will write down in the 3 statements. IS: $80 write-down shows up in the Pre-Tax Income line and after 40% tax, net income goes down by $32. In SCF, the write-down is a non-cash expense, so we add it back - and therefore CF from Operations is up $32 (-48 + 80). There are no changes under CF for Investing but under CF for Financing, it is down $100 from the loan payback leaving net change CF down $68; BS: Cash is now down $68 and assets is down $80, total Assets is down $148. Liabilities is down $100 and SE is down 48$ to balanace out.",
      "question" : "Question 14: At the start of Year 3, the factories all break down and the value of the equipment is written down to $0. The loan must also be paid back now. Walk me through the 3 statements."
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "IS: No changes SCF: CF Operations is down $10 from purchasing the assets, net change in CF is down $10 BS: Cash is down $10 but inventory is up $10 so they balance out.",
      "question" : "Question 15: Now let’s look at a different scenario and assume Apple is ordering $10 of additional iPod inventory, using cash on hand. They order the inventory, but they have not manufactured or sold anything yet – what happens to the 3 statements?"
    },
    "16" : {
      "answer" : "IS: Revenue is up by $20, COGS is up by $10, pre-tax income is up $10 so after taxes, net income is up $6. SCF: Net income at the top is up $6, add another $10 from CF Operations from selling the inventory therefore net change in CF is up $16 BS: Cash is up $16, inventory is down $10 so Assets is up $6. To balance it out, SE goes down by $6.",
      "question" : "Question 16: Now let’s say they sell the iPods for revenue of $20, at a cost of $10. Walk me through the 3 statements under this scenario."
    },
    "17" : {
      "answer" : "It is common in 2 scenarios: 1) Leveraged buyouts with dividend recapitalizations - it means that the owner of the company has taken out a large portion of its equity (usually in the form of cash), which can sometimes turn the number negative 2) It can also happen if the company has been losing money consistently and therefore has a declining Retained Earnings balance, which is a portion of SE. SE never turns negative IMMEDIATELY after an LBO, it only happens following a dividend recap or continued net loses.",
      "question" : "Question 17: Could you ever end up with negative shareholders’ equity? What does it mean?"
    },
    "18" : {
      "answer" : "Working Capital = Current Assets - Current Liabilities; If it's positive, it means a company can pay off its short-term liabilities with its short-term assets. It is often presented as a financial metric and its magnitude and sign (negative and positive) tells you whether or not the company is 'sound'. Bankers look at Operating Working Capital more commonly in models, and that is defined as (Current Assets - Cash and Cash Equivalents) - (Current Liabilities - Debt).",
      "question" : "Question 18: What is working capital? How is it used?"
    },
    "19" : {
      "answer" : "Not necessarily. It depends on the type of company and the specific situation - here are a few different things it could mean: 1) Some companies with subscriptions or longer-term contracts often have negative WC because of high deferred revenue balances. 2) Retail and restaurant companies like Amazon, Walk-Mart, and McDonald's often have negative WC because customers pay upfront - so they can use the cash generated to pay off their Accounts Payable rather than keeping a large cash balance on-hand. This can be a sign of business efficiency. 3) In other cases, negative WC could point to financial trouble or possible bankruptcy (for example, when customer's don't pay quickly and upfront and the company is carrying a high debt balance).",
      "question" : "Question 19: What does negative Working Capital mean? Is that a bad sign?"
    },
    "20" : {
      "answer" : "IS: the $100 write-down shows up in the Pre-Tax Income line. With a 40% tax rate, Net Income declines by $60 SCF: This gets brought over to the SCF, and the write-down gets added back because its a non-cash expense - therefore CF from Operations is up $40. Overall, net change in cash is up $40 BS: Cash is up $40, assets is down $100 so SE needs to go down by $60 to balance.",
      "question" : "Question 20: Recently, banks have been writing down their assets and taking huge quarterly losses. Walk me through what happens on the 3 statements when there’s a write- down of $100."
    },
    "21" : {
      "answer" : "First, confirm what type of 'bailout' this is - Debt? Equity? A combination? The most common scenario here is an equity investment from the government so here's what happens: 1) IS: No changes 2) SCF: Cash Flow from Financing goes up $100 to reflect the government investment, so the Net Change in Cash is up by $100 3) BS: Cash is up by $100, so Assets are up by $100; on the other side SE is up by $100 to make it balance.",
      "question" : "Question 21: Walk me through a $100 'bailout' of a company and how it affects the 3 statements."
    },
    "22" : {
      "answer" : "This is counter intuitive. When a liability is wrriten down you record it as a GAIN on the IS (with an asset-down, it's a loss) = so Pre-Tax Income goes up by $100 due to its write-down. Assuming a 40% tax rate, Net Income is up $60 SCF: Net income is up $60 but subtract that debt-write down so CF from Operations is down by $40, and Net Change in Cash is down by $40. BS: Cash is down by $40 so Assets are down by $40. Debt is down by $100 so SE goes up by $60 to balance the two sides out. Writing down debt actually benefits companies accounting-wise.",
      "question" : "Question 22: Walk me through a $100 write-down of debt – as in OWED debt, a liability – on a company’s balance sheet and how it affects the 3 statements."
    },
    "23" : {
      "answer" : "3 examples comes to mind: 1) Web-based subscription software 2) Cell-phone carriers that sell annual contracts 3) Magazine publishers that sell subscription ... Companies that agree to services in the future often collect cash upfront to ensure stable revenue - this makes investors happy as well since they can better predict a company's performance. Per the rules of GAAP, you only record revenue when you actually perform the services - so the company would not record everything as revenue right away.",
      "question" : "Question 23: When would a company collect cash from a customer and not record it as revenue?"
    },
    "24" : {
      "answer" : "Usually it goes into Deferred Revenue balance on the BS under liabilities. Over time, as the services are performed, the Deferred Revenue balance 'turns into' real revenue on the Income Statement.",
      "question" : "Question 24: If cash collected is not recorded as revenue, what happens to it?"
    },
    "25" : {
      "answer" : "Accounts receivables has not yet been collected in cash from customers, whereas deferred revenue has been. Accounts receivable is how much the company is waiting to collect where Deferred Revenue is how much the company is waiting to record as revenue.",
      "question" : "Question 25: What’s the difference between accounts receivable and deferred revenue?"
    },
    "26" : {
      "answer" : "It is dependant on the company, particularly the industry but generally the AR days are in the 40-50 day range, though it is higher for companies selling high-end items and it might be lower for smaller, lower-transaction value companies.",
      "question" : "Question 26: How long does it usually take for a company to collect its accounts receivable balance?"
    },
    "27" : {
      "answer" : "Cash-based accounting recognizes revenue and expenses when cash is actually received or paid out; accrual accounting recognizes revenue when collection is reasonably certain and recognizes expenses when they are incurred rather than when they are paid out in cash. Most large companies use accrual accounting because paying with credit cards and lines of credit is so prevalent these days; very small businesses may use cash-based accounting to simplify their financial statements.",
      "question" : "Question 27: What’s the difference between cash-based and accrual accounting?"
    },
    "28" : {
      "answer" : "In cash-based accounting, the revenue would not show up until the company charges the customer's credit card, receives authorization, and deposits the funds in its bank account - at which point it would show up as both Revenue on the Income Statement and Cash on the Balance Sheet. In Accrual accounting, it would show up as Revenue right away but instead of appearing as Cash on the BS, it appears as Accounts Payable at first. Then, when the cash is deposited it gets converted into cash on the BS.",
      "question" : "Question 28: Let’s say a customer pays for a TV with a credit card. What would this look like under cash-based vs. accrual accounting?"
    },
    "29" : {
      "answer" : "If the asset has a useful life of over 1 year, it is capitalized (put on the BS rather than shown as an expense on the IS). It is depreciated (tangible assets) or amortized (intangible assets) over a certain number of years. Purchases like factories, equipment and land all last longer than a year and therefore show up on the BS. Employee salaries and the cost of manufacturing products (COGS) only cover a short period of operations and therefore show up on the IS as normal expenses instead.",
      "question" : "Question 29: How do you decide when to capitalize rather than expense a purchase?"
    },
    "30" : {
      "answer" : "These days, many companies have 'non-cash' charges such as Amortization of Intangibles, Stock-based compensation, and Deferred REvenue Write-Downs in their Income Statements. As a result, some argue that IS under GAAP no longer reflects how profitable most companies truly are. Non-GAAP earnings are almost always higher because these expenses are excluded.",
      "question" : "Question 30: Why do companies report both GAAP and non-GAAP (or 'Pro Forma') earnings?"
    },
    "31" : {
      "answer" : "1) The company is spending too much on Capital Expenditures - these are not reflected at all in EBITDA, but it could still be cash-flow negative 2) The company has high interest expense and is no longer able to afford its debt 3) The company's debt all matures on one date and it is unable to refinance it due to a 'credit crunch' - and it runs out of cash completely when paying back debt 4) It has significant one-time charges (from litigation, for example) and those are high enough to bankrupt the company ... EBITDA excludes investment in (and depreciation of) long term assets, interest and one-time charges - and all those could end up bankrupting the company.",
      "question" : "Question 31: A company has had positive EBITDA for the past 10 years, but it recently went bankrupt. How could this happen?"
    },
    "32" : {
      "answer" : "Usually this happens when a company has been acquired and the acquirer re-assesses its intangible assets (such as customers, brand, intellectual property, talent) and finds that they are significantly less than they originally thought. It often happens in acquisitions where the buyer 'overpaid' for the seller and can result in a large net loss on the IS (see Ebay/Skype). It can also happen when a company discontinues part of its operation and must impair the associated goodwill.",
      "question" : "Question 32: Normally Goodwill remains constant on the Balance Sheet – why would it be impaired and what does Goodwill Impairment mean?"
    },
    "33" : {
      "answer" : "Technically, Goodwill can increase if the company re-assesses its value and finds that it is worth more but that is rare. Usually what happens is 1 of 2 scenarios: 1) The company gets acquired or bought out and Goodwill changes as a result, since it's an accounting 'plug' for the purchase price in an acquisition 2) The company acquires another company and pays more than what its assets are worth - this is then reflected in the Goodwill number",
      "question" : "Question 33: Under what circumstances would Goodwill increase?"
    }
  },
  "accounting-advanced" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "1) GAAP is accrual-based but tax is cash-based 2) GAAP uses straight-line depreciation or a few other methods whereas tax accounting is different (accelerated depreciation) 3) GAAP is more complex and more accurately tracks assets/liabilities whereas tax accounting is only concerned with revenue/expenses in the current period and what income tax you owe",
      "question" : "Question 1: How is GAAP accounting different from tax accounting?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "They arise because of temporary differences between what a company can deduct for cash tax purposes vs. what they can deduct for book tax purposes. Deferred Tax Liabilities arise when you have a tax expense on the IS but you haven't actually paid that tax in cold, hard cash yet; Deferred Tax Assets arise when you pay taxes in cash but haven't expensed them on the IS yet. The most common way they occur is with asset write-ups and write-downs in M&A deals - an asset write-up will produce a deferred tax liability while a write-down will produce a deferred tax asset.",
      "question" : "Question 2: What are deferred tax assets/liabilities and how do they arise?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "There are 2 ways you could do this: a bottom-up or top-down build: Bottoms-up) Start with individual products/customers, estimate the average sale value or customer value, and then the growth rate in sales and sale values to tie everything together Tops-Down) Start with 'big-picture' metrics like overall market size, then estimate the company's market share and how that will change in coming years, and multiply to get their revenue ... Bottoms-up is more common and is taken more seriously because estimating 'big picture' numbers is almost impossible.",
      "question" : "Question 3: Walk me through how you create a revenue model for a company."
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "To do a true bottoms-up build, you start with each different department of a company, the # of employees in each, the average salary, bonuses, and benefits, and then make assumptions on those going forward. Usually you assume that the number of employees is tied to revenue, and then you assume growth rates for salary, bonuses, benefits, and other metrics. COGS should be tied directly to Revenue and each 'unit' produced should incur an expense. Other items such as rent, Capital Expenditures, and miscellaneous expenses are either linked to the company's internal plans for build expansion plans (if they have them) or to Revenue for a more simple model.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Walk me through how you create an expense model for a company."
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Use estimates. For the revenue, if you don't have enough information to look at separate product lines or divisions of the company, you can just assume a simple growth rate into future years. For the expenses, if you don't have employee-level information then you can just assume that major expenses like SG&A are a percent of revenue and carry that assumption forward.",
      "question" : "Question 5: Let’s say we’re trying to create these models but don’t have enough information or the company doesn’t tell us enough in its filings – what do we do?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "Common items include: 1) Common stock: simply the par value of however much stock the company has issued 2) Retained Earnings: How much of the company's Net Income it has 'saved up' over time 3) Additional Paid in Capital: this keeps track of how much stock based compensation has been issued and how much new stock employees excercising option have created 4) Treasury Stock: The dollar amount of shares that the company has bought back 5) Accumulated Other Comprehensive Income: This is a 'catch' that includes other items that don't fit anywhere else, like the effect of foreign currency exchange rates changing",
      "question" : "Question 6: Walk me through the major items in Shareholders’ Equity."
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "Retained Earnings = Old Retained Earnings + Net Income - Dividends Issued ... If you're calculating Retained Earnings for the current year, take last year's RE, add this year's Net Income, and subtract however much the company paid out in dividends.",
      "question" : "Question 7: Walk me through what flows into Retained Earnings."
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "APIC = Old APIC + Stock Based Compensation + Stock Created by Option Excercise",
      "question" : "Question 8: Walk me through what flows into Additional Paid-In Capital (APIC)."
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "The statement shows the major items that comprise SE and how we arrive at each of them using the numbers elsewhere in the statement. You don't use it too much, but it can be helpful for analyzing companies with unusual stock-based compensation and stock option situations.",
      "question" : "Question 9: What is the Statement of Shareholders’ Equity and why do we use it?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "1) Restructuring Charges 2) Goodwill Impairment 3) Legal Expenses 4) Asset Write-Downs 5) Bad-Debt Expenses 6) Disaster Expenses 7) Accounting Problem Changes ... Note that to be an 'add back' or 'non-recurring' charge for EBITDA/EBIT purposes, it needs to affect Operating Income on the INcome Statement. So if you have one of these charges 'below the line' then you do not add it back for the EBITDA/EBIT calculation. Also note that you do add back Depreciation, Amortization, and sometimes Stock-Based Compensation for EBITDA/EBIT, but these are not 'non-recurring charges' because all companies have them every year - these are just non-cash charges.",
      "question" : "Question 10: What are examples of non-recurring charges we need to add back to a company’s EBIT / EBITDA when looking at its financial statements?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "Normally you make very simple assumptions here and assume these are percentages of revenue, operating expenses, or COGS. Examples: 1) AR = % of Revenue 2) Deferred Revenue = % of Revenue 3) Accounts Payable = % of COGS 4) Accrued Expenses = % of Operating Expenses ... Then you either carry the same percentages across in future years or assume slight changes depending on the company.",
      "question" : "Question 11: How do you project Balance Sheet items like Accounts Receivable and Accrued Expenses in a 3-statement model?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "The simple way: project each as a % of revenue or previous PP&E. The most complex way: create a PP&E schedule that splits out different assets by their useful lives, assume straight-line depreciation over each asset's useful life, and then assumes Capital Expenditures based on what the company has invested historically.",
      "question" : "Question 12: How should you project Depreciation & Capital Expenditures?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "The 'quick and diry' way to do this: reduce the Taxable Income by the portion of the NOLs that you can use each year, apply the same tax rate, and then subtract that new Tax number from your old Pretax Income number (which should stay the same). The way you should do this: create a book vs cash tax schedule where you calculate the Taxable Income based on NOLs, and then look at what you would pay in taxes without the NOLs. Then you book the difference as an increase to the Deferred Tax Liability on the BS. This method reflects the fact that you're saving on cash flow - since the DTL, a liability, is rising - but correctly separates the NOL impact into book vs cash taxes.",
      "question" : "Question 13: How do Net Operating Losses (NOLs) affect a company’s 3 statements?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "Operating leases are used for short-term leasing of equipment and property, and do not involve ownership or anything. Operating lease expenses show up as operating expenses on the IS. Capital leases are used for longer-term items and give the lease ownership rights; they depreciate and incur interest payments, and are counted as debt. A lease is a capital lease if any one of the following 4 conditions is true: 1) if there is a transfer of ownership at the end of the term 2) if there is an option to purchase the asset at a bargain price at the end of the term 3) if the term of the lease is greater than 75% of the useful life of the asset 4) if the present value of the lease payments is greater than 90% of the asset's fair market value",
      "question" : "Question 14: What’s the difference between capital leases and operating leases?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "This happens if D&A is embedded in other Income Statement line items. When this ahppens, you need to use the SCF number to arrive at EBITDA because otherwise you're undercounting D&A.",
      "question" : "Question 15: Why would the Depreciation & Amortization number on the Income Statement be different from what’s on the Cash Flow Statement?"
    }
  },
  "enterprise-EV" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Enterprise Value represents the value of the company that is attributable to all investors; Equity Value only represents the portion available to shareholders (equity investors). You look at both because Equity Value is the number the public-at-large sees while Enterprise Value is its true value.",
      "question" : "Question 1: Why do we look at both Enterprise Value and Equity Value?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "Enterprise Value, because that's how much an acquirer really 'pays' and includes the often mandatory debt payment.",
      "question" : "Question 2: When looking at an acquisition of a company, do you pay more attention to Enterprise or Equity Value?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Enterprise Value = Equity Value + Debt + Preferred Stock + Minority Interest - Cash ... This formula does not tell the whole story and can get more complex - see the Advanced Questions. Most of the time you can get away with stating this formula in an interview, though.",
      "question" : "Question 3: What’s the formula for Enterprise Value?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "Whenever a company owns over 50% of another company, it is required to report the financial performance of the other company as part of its own performance. So even thought it doesn't own 100%, it reports 100% of the majority-owned subsidiary's financial performance. In keep with the 'apples-to-apples' theme, you must add Minority Interest to get to Enterprise Value so that the numerator and denominator both reflect 100% of the majority-owned subsidiary.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Why do you need to add Minority Interest to Enterprise Value?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Take the basic share count and add in the dilutive effect of stock options and any other dilutive securities, such as warrants, convertible debt or convertible preferred stock. To calculate the dilutive effect of options, you use the Treasury Stock Method.",
      "question" : "Question 5: How do you calculate fully diluted shares?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "Its basic equity value is $1000 ($100 x 10 = $1000). To calculate the dilutive effect of the options, first you note that the options are all 'in-the-money' - their excercise price is less than the current share price. When these options are excercised, there will be 10 new shares created - so the share count is now 110 rather than 100. However, this doesn't tell the entire story. In order to excercise the options, we had to 'pay' the company $5 for each option (the excercise price). As a result, it now has $50 additional cash, which it now use to buy back 5 of the new shares we created. So the fully diluted share count is 105, and the fully diluted equity value is $1050.",
      "question" : "Question 6: Let’s say a company has 100 shares outstanding, at a share price of $10 each. It also has 10 options outstanding at an exercise price of $5 each – what is its fully diluted equity value?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "$1000. In this case, the options' excercise price is above the current share price, so they have no dilutive effect.",
      "question" : "Question 7: Let’s say a company has 100 shares outstanding, at a share price of $10 each. It also has 10 options outstanding at an exercise price of $15 each – what is its fully diluted equity value?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "Official Reason: Cash is subtracted because it's considered a non-operating asset and because Euity Value implicitly accounts for it ... The Way I Think About It: In an acquisition, the buyer would 'get' the cash of the seller, so it effectively pays less for the company based on how large its cash balance is. Remember, Enterprise Value (EV) tells us how much you'd really have to 'pay' to acquire another company ... It's not always accurate because technically you should be subtracting only excess cash - the amount of cash a company has above the minimum cash it requires to operate.",
      "question" : "Question 8: Why do you subtract cash in the formula for Enterprise Value? Is that always accurate?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "In most cases, yes, because the terms of a debt agreement usually says that debt must be refinanced in an acquisition. And in most cases a buyer will pay off a seller's debt, so its accurate to say that any debt 'adds' to the purchase price. However, there could always be exceptions where the buyer does not pay off the debt. These are rare and I've personally never seen it, but once again 'never say never' applies.",
      "question" : "Question 9: Is it always accurate to add Debt to Equity Value when calculating Enterprise Value?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "Yes it means that the company has an extremely large cash balance, or an extremely low market capitalization (or both). You see it with: 1) Companies on the brink of bankruptcy 2) Financial institutions, such as banks, that have large cash balances",
      "question" : "Question 10: Could a company have a negative Enterprise Value? What would that mean?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "No. This is not possible because you cannot have a negative share count and you cannot have a negative share price.",
      "question" : "Question 11: Could a company have a negative Equity Value? What would that mean?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "Preferred stock pays out a fixed dividend, and the preferred stock holders also have a higher claim to a company's assets than equity investors do. As a result, it is seen as more similar to debt than common stock.",
      "question" : "Question 12: Why do we add Preferred Stock to get to Enterprise Value?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "If the convertible bonds are 'in-the-money', meaning that the conversion price is below the current share price, then you count them as additional dilution to the Equity Value; if they're 'out-of-the-money' then you count the face value of the convertibles as part of the company's Debt.",
      "question" : "Question 13: How do you account for convertible bonds in the Enterprise Value formula?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "This gets confusing because of the different units involved. First, note that these convertible bonds are 'in-the-money' because the company's share price is $100 but the conversion price is $50. So we count them as additional shares rather than debt. Next, we need to divide the value of the convertible bonds - $10 million - by teh par value - $1000 - to figure out how many individual bonds we get ($10 million / $1000 = 1,0000 convertible bonds). Next, we need to figure out how many shares this number represents. The number of shares per bond is the par value divided by the conversion price ($1,000 / $50 = 20 shares per bond). So we have 200,000 new shares (10,000 * 20) created by the convertibles, giving us 1.2 million diluted shares outstanding. WE DO NOT USE THE TREASURY METHOD WITH CONVERTIBLES because the company is not 'receiving' any cash from us.",
      "question" : "Question 14: A company has 1 million shares outstanding at a value of $100 per share. It also has $10 million of convertible bonds, with par value of $1,000 and a conversion price of $50. How do I calculate diluted shares outstanding?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "Equity value is the MARKET VALUE and SE is the BOOK VALUE. Equity value can never be negative because shares outstanding and share prices can never be negative, whereas SE could be any value. For healthy companies, Equity Value usually far exceeds Shareholder's Equity.",
      "question" : "Question 15: What’s the difference between Equity Value and Shareholders’ Equity?"
    }
  },
  "advanced-enterprise-EV" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "Yes - it's too simple. There are lots of other things you need to add into the formula with real comapnies: 1) Net Operating Losses - should be valued and arguably added in, similar to cash (-) 2) Long-term Investment - These should be counted similar to cash (-) 3) Equity Investments - Any investments in other companies should also be added in, similar to cash (though they might be discounted) 4) Capital Leases - like debt, these have interest payments - so they should be added in like debt (+) 5) (Some) Operating Leases - Sometimes you need to convert operating leases to capital leases and add them as well (+) 6) Pension Obligations - sometimes these are counted as debt (+)",
      "question" : "Question 1: Are there any problems with the Enterprise Value formula you just gave me?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "Technically, you should use market value for everything. In practice, however you usually use market value only for Equity Value portion, because it's almost impossible to establish market values for the rest of the items in the formula - so you just take the numbers from the company's Balance Sheet",
      "question" : "Question 2: Should you use the book value or market value of each item when calculating Enterprise Value?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "There's no strict 'rule' here but most bankers would say that anything over 10% is odd. If your basic Equity Value is $100 million and the diluted Equity Value is $115 million, you might want to check your calculations - it's not necessarily wrong, but over 10% dilution is unusual for most companies.",
      "question" : "Question 3: What percentage dilution in Equity Value is “too high?”"
    }
  },
  "valuation" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "1) Comparable Companies 2) Precedent Transactions 3) DCF (Discounted Cash Flow)",
      "question" : "Question 1: What are the 3 major valuation methodologies?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "Trick question - there is no ranking that always holds. In general, Precedent Transactions will be higher than Comparable Companies due to the Control Premium built into acquisitions. Beyond that, a DCF could go either way and it's best to say that it's more variable than other methodologies. Often it produces the highest value, but it can produce the lowest value as well depending on your assumptions.",
      "question" : "Question 2: Rank the 3 valuation methodologies from highest to lowest expected value."
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "You would not use a DCF if the company has unstable or unpredictable cash dlows (tech or bio-tech startup) or when debt and working capital serve a fundamentally different role. For example, banks and financial institutions do not re-invest debt and working capital is a huge part of their BS - so you wouldn't use a DCF for such companies.",
      "question" : "Question 3: When would you not use a DCF in a Valuation?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "1) Liquidation Valuation: valuing a company's assets, assuming they are sold off and then subtracting liabilities to determine how much capital, if any, equity investors receive 2) Replacement Value - valuing a company based on the cost of replacing its assets 3) LBO Analysis - determining how much a PE firm could pay for a company to hit a 'target' IRR, usually in the 20-25% range 4) Sum of the Parts - valuing each division of a company separately and adding them together at the end 5) M&A Premium Analysis - analyzing M&A deals and figuring out the premium that each buyer paid, and using this to establish what your company is worth 6) Future Share Price Analyssis -Projecting a company's share price based on the P/E multiples of the public company comparables, then discounting it back to its present value",
      "question" : "Question 4: What other Valuation methodologies are there?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "This is most common in bankruptcy scenarios and is used to see whether equity shareholders will receive any capital after the company's debts have been paid off. It is often used to advise struggling businesses on whether it's better to sell off assets separately or to try and sell the entire company.",
      "question" : "Question 5: When would you use a Liquidation Valuation?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "This is most often used when a company has completely different, unrelated divisions -a conglomerate like General Electric, for example. If you have a plastics division, a TV and entertainment divsion, an energy division, a consumer financing division and a technology division, value each one separately, and then add them together to get the Combined Value.",
      "question" : "Question 6: When would you use Sum of the Parts?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "Obviously you use this whenever you're looking at a Leveraged Buyout - but it is also used to establish how much a private equity firm could pay, which is usually lower than what companies would pay. It is often used to set a 'floor' on a possible Valuation for the company you're looking at.",
      "question" : "Question 7: When do you use an LBO Analysis as part of your Valuation?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "1) EV/Revenue 2) EV/EBITDA 3) EV/EBIT 4) P/E (Share Price/Earnings Per Share) 5) P/BV (Share Price/Book Value)",
      "question" : "Question 8: What are the most common multiples used in Valuation?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "1) Technology (Internet): EV/Unique Visitors, EV/Pageviews 2) Retail/Airlines: EV/EBITDAR (Earnings Before Interest, Taxes, Depreciation, Amortization and Rent) 3) Energy: P/MCFE, P/MCFE/D (MCFE = 1 Million Cubic Foot Equivalent, MCFE/D = MCFE per Day), P/Nav (Share Price/Net Asset Value) 4) Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs): Price/FFO,Price/AFFO (Funds from Operations, Adjust Funds from Operations) ... Technology and Energy should be straightforward -you're looking at traffic and energy reserves as value drivers rather than revenue or profit. For Retail/Airlines, you often remove Rent because it is a major expense and one that varies significantly between different types of companies. For REITs, FFO is a common metric that adds back Depreciation and subtracts gains on the sale of property. Depreciation is a non-cash yet extremely large expense in real estate, and gains on sales of properties aare assumed to be non-recurring, as FFO is viewed as a 'normalized' picture of the cash flow the REIT is generating.",
      "question" : "Question 9: What are some examples of industry-specific multiples?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "You use Enterprise Value because those scientists or subscribers are 'available' to all the investors (both debt and equity) in a company. The same logic doesn't apply to everything, though - you need to think through the multiple and see which investors the particular metric is 'available' to.",
      "question" : "Question 10: When you’re looking at an industry-specific multiple like EV / Scientists or EV / Subscribers, why do you use Enterprise Value rather than Equity Value?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "Technically it could go either way, but in most cases the LBO will give you a lower valuation. Here's the easiest way to think about it: with an LBO, you do not get any value from the cash flows of a company in between Year 1 and the final year - you're only valuing it based on its terminal value. With a DCF, by contrast, you're taking into accoun BOTH the company's cash flows in between and its terminal value, so values tend to be higher. Note: Unlike a DCF, an LBO model by itself does not give a specific valuation. Instead, you set a desired IRR and determine how much you would pay for the company (the valuation) based on that.",
      "question" : "Question 11: Would an LBO or DCF give a higher valuation?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "Usually you use a 'football field' chart where you show the valuation range implied by each methodology. You ALWAYS show a range rather than one specific number.",
      "question" : "Question 12: How would you present these Valuation methodologies to a company or its investors?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "The same way you would value a company: by looking at what comparable apple trees are worth (relative valuation) and the value of the apple tree's cash flows (intrinsic valuation).",
      "question" : "Question 13: How would you value an apple tree?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "EBITDA is available to all investors in the company - rather than just equity holders. Similarly, Enterprise Value is also available to all shareholders so it makes sense to pair them together. Equity Value/EBITDA, however, is comparing apples to oranges because Equity Value does not reflect the company's entire capital structure - only the part availableto equity investors.",
      "question" : "Question 14: Why can’t you use Equity Value / EBITDA as a multiple rather than Enterprise Value / EBITDA?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "This is highly unusual, but it could happen if the company had substantial hard assets but the market was severely undervaluing it for a specific reason (such as an earnings miss or cyclicality). As a result, the company's Comparable Companies and Precedent Transactions would likely produce lower values as well- if its assets were valued highly enough, Liquidation Valuation might give a higher value than other methodologies.",
      "question" : "Question 15: When would a Liquidation Valuation produce the highest value?"
    },
    "16" : {
      "answer" : "You would use Comparable Companies and Precedent Transactions and look at more 'creative' muliples such as EV/Unique Visitors, EV/Pageviews rather than EV/EBITDA or EV/Revenue. You would NOT use a 'far in the future DCF' because you can't reasonably predict cash flow, use other metrics - don't try to predict cash flow anyway!",
      "question" : "Question 16: Let’s go back to 2004 and look at Facebook back when it had no profit and no revenue. How would you value it?"
    },
    "17" : {
      "answer" : "Trick Question. For UNLEVERED Free Cash Flow, you would use Enterprise Value, for Levered Free Cash Flow, you would use Equity Value. Remember, Unlevered FCF excludes Interest and thus represents money available to all investors, whereas Levered already includes Interest and the money is therefore only available to equity investors. Debt investors have already 'been paid' with the interest payments they received.",
      "question" : "Question 17: What would you use in conjunction with Free Cash Flow multiples – Equity Value or Enterprise Value?"
    },
    "18" : {
      "answer" : "Never say never. It's very rare to see this, but sometimes large financial institutions with big cash balances have negative Enterprise Values - so you might use Equity Value/Revenue instead. You might see Equity Value/Revenue if you've listed a set of financial and non-financial companies on a slide, you're showing Revenue multiples for the financial companies, and you want to show something similar for the financials.",
      "question" : "Question 18: You never use Equity Value / EBITDA, but are there any cases where you might use Equity Value / Revenue?"
    },
    "19" : {
      "answer" : "There are 3 main ways to select companies and transactions: 1) Industry Classification 2) Financial Critera (Revenue, EBITDA etc...) 3) Geography ... For Precendent Transactions, you often limit the set based on date and only look at transactioins within the past 1-2 years. The most important factor is industry - that is always used to screen companies/transactions, and the rest may or may not be used depending on how specific you want to be. Here are a few examples: Comparable Company Screen:Oil and gas producers with market caps over $5b; CCS:Digital media companies with over $100m in revenue ... Precendent Transaction Screen:Airline M&A transactions over the past 2 years involving sellers with over $1b in revenue; PTS:Retail M&A transactions over the past year",
      "question" : "Question 19: How do you select Comparable Companies / Precedent Transactions?"
    },
    "20" : {
      "answer" : "Sometimes this simple fact getslost in discussion of Valuation methodologies. You take the median multiple of a set of companies or transactions, and then multiply it by the relevant metric from the company you're valuing. Example: If the median EBITDA multiple from your set of Precendent Transactions is 8x and your company's EBITDA is $500 million, the implied Enterprise Value would be $4 billion.",
      "question" : "Question 20: How do you apply the 3 valuation methodologies to actually get a value for the company you’re looking at?"
    },
    "21" : {
      "answer" : "Usually you use it in pitch books and in client presentations when you're providing updates and telling them what they should expect for their own valuation. It's also used right before a deal closes in a Fairness Opinion, a document a bank creates that 'proves' the value their client is paying or receiving is 'fair' from a financial point of view. Valuations can also be used in defense analyses, merger models, LBO models, DCFs (because terminal multiples are based off of comps) and pretty much anything else in finance.",
      "question" : "Question 21: What do you actually use a valuation for?"
    },
    "22" : {
      "answer" : "This could happen for a number of reasons: 1) The company has just reported earnings well-above expectations and its stock price has risen recently 2) It has some type of competitive advantage not reflected in its financial, such as a key patent or other intellectual property",
      "question" : "Question 22: Why would a company with similar growth and profitability to its Comparable Companies be valued at a premium?"
    },
    "23" : {
      "answer" : "1) No company is 100% comparable to another company2) The stock market is 'emotional' - your multiples might be dramatically higher or lower on certain dates depending on the market's movement 3) Share prices for small companies wtihin thinly-traded stocks may not reflect their full value",
      "question" : "Question 23: What are the flaws with public company comparables?"
    },
    "24" : {
      "answer" : "1) Look at the 75th percentile or higher for the multiples rather than the Medians 2) Add in a premium to some of the multiples 3) Use more aggressive projections for the company ... In practice, you rarely do all of the above - theses are just possibilities.",
      "question" : "Question 24: How do you take into account a company’s competitive advantage in a valuation?"
    },
    "25" : {
      "answer" : "There's no 'rule' that you have to do this, but in most cases you do because you want to use values from the middle range of the set. But if the company you're valuing is distressed, is not performing well, or is at a competitive disadvantage, you might use the 25th percentile or something in the lower range instead - and vice versa if it's doing well.",
      "question" : "Question 25: Do you ALWAYS use the median multiple of a set of public company comparables or precedent transactions?"
    },
    "26" : {
      "answer" : "Sometimes this happens when there is a substantial mismatch between the M&A market and the public market. For example, no public companies have been acquired recently but there have been a lot of small private companies acquired at extremely low valuations. For the most part, this generalization is true but keep in mind that there are exceptions to almost every 'rule' in finance.",
      "question" : "Question 26: You mentioned that Precedent Transactions usually produce a higher value than Comparable Companies – can you think of a situation where this is not the case?"
    },
    "27" : {
      "answer" : "1) Past transactions are rarely 100% comparable - the transaction structure, size of the company, and market sentiment all have huge effects 2) Data on precedent transactions is generally more difficult to find than it is for public company comparables, especially for acquisitions of small private companies",
      "question" : "Question 27: What are some flaws with precedent transactions?"
    },
    "28" : {
      "answer" : "Possible reasons: 1) One process was more competitive and had a lot more companies bidding on the target 2) One company had recent bad news or depressed stock price so it was acquired at a discount 3) They were in industries with different median multiples",
      "question" : "Question 28: Two companies have the exact same financial profile and are bought by the same acquirer, but the EBITDA multiple for one transaction is twice the multiple of the other transaction – how could this happen?"
    },
    "29" : {
      "answer" : "Warren Buffett once famously said, 'Does management think the tooth fair pays for capital expenditures?' He dislikes EBITDA because it excludes the often sizeable Capital Expenditures companies make and hides how much cash they are actually using to finance their operations. In some industries thereis also a large gap between EBIT and EBITDA -anything that is very capital-intensive, for example, will show a big disparity.",
      "question" : "Question 29: Why does Warren Buffett prefer EBIT multiples to EBITDA multiples?"
    },
    "30" : {
      "answer" : "P/E depends on the company's capital structure whereas EV/EBIT and EV/EBITDA are capital-structure neutral. Therefore, you use P/E for banks, financial institutions, and other companies where interest payments/expenses are critical. But shares -the ability to buy individual pieces of a company rather than the whole thing - can be either liquid (if it's public) or illiquid (if it's private). Some shares of public companies are always more liquid, you would discount public company comparable multiples to account for this.",
      "question" : "Question 30: The EV / EBIT, EV / EBITDA, and P / E multiples all measure a company’s profitability. What’s the difference between them, and when do you use each one?"
    },
    "31" : {
      "answer" : "Only in the context of precedent transactions - it would make no sense to include them for public company comparables or as part of the Cost of Equity/WACC calculation in a DCF because they are not public and therefore have no values for market cap or Beta.",
      "question" : "Question 31: Can you use private companies as part of your valuation?"
    },
    "32" : {
      "answer" : "You would pay more for theone where you lease the machines. Enterprise Value would be the same for both companies, but with the depreciated situation the charge is not reflected in EBITDA - so EBITDA is higher, and the EV/EBITDA multiple is lower as a result. For the leased situation, the lease would show up in SG&A so it would be reflected in EBITDA, making EBITDA lower and the EV/EBITDA multiple higher.",
      "question" : "Question 32: If you were buying a vending machine business, would you pay a higher multiple for a business where you owned the machines and they depreciated normally, or one in which you leased the machines? The cost of depreciation and lease are the same dollar amounts and everything else is held constant."
    },
    "33" : {
      "answer" : "You would use the same methodologies as with public companies: public company comparables, precedent transactions, and DCF. But there are some differences: 1) You might apply a 10-15% (or more) discount to the public company comparable multiples because the private company you're valuing is not as 'liquid' as the public comps 2) You can't use a premium analysis or future share price analysis because a private company doesn't have a share price 3) Your valuation shows the EV for the company as opposed to the implied per-share price with public companies 4) A DCF gets tricky because a pivate company doesn't have a market capitalization or Beta - you would probably just estimate WACC based on the public comps' WACC rather than trying to calculate it",
      "question" : "Question 33: How do you value a private company?"
    },
    "34" : {
      "answer" : "There's no discount because with precedent transactions, you're acquiring the entire company - once it's acquired, the shares immediately become illiquid. But shares - the ability to buy individual 'pieces' of a company rather than the whole thing - can be either liquid (if it's public) or illiquid (if it's private). Since shares of public companies are always more liquid, you would discount company comparable multiples to account for this.",
      "question" : "Question 34: Let’s say we’re valuing a private company. Why might we discount the public company comparable multiples but not the precedent transaction multiples?"
    },
    "35" : {
      "answer" : "Only in the context of precedent transactions - it would make no sense to include them for public company comparables or as part of the Cost of Equity/WACC calculation in a DCF because they are not public and therefore have no values for market cap or Beta.",
      "question" : "Question 35: Can you use private companies as part of your valuation?"
    }
  },
  "advanced-valuation" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "You mostly use the same methodologies, except: 1) You look at P/E and P/BV (Book Value) multiples rather than EV/Revenue, EV/EBITDA, and other 'normal' multiples, since banks have unique capital structures 2) You pay more attention to bank-specific metrics like NAV (Net Asset Value) and you might screen companies and precedent transactions based on those 3) Rather than a DCF, you use a Divident Discount Model (DDM) which is similar but is based on the present value of the company's dividends rather than it's free cash flows ... You need to use these methodologies and multiples because interest is a critical component of a bank's revenue and because debt is part of its business model rather than just a way to finance acquisitions or expand the business.",
      "question" : "Question 1: How do you value banks and financial institutions differently from other companies?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "1) Unlike normal valuations, for an IPO Valuation we only care about public company comparables 2) After picking the public company comparables we decide on the most relevant multiple to use and tehne estimate our company's Enterprise Value based on that 3) Once we have the EV, we work backward to get the Equity Value AND ALSO SUBTRACT THE IPO PROCEEDS BECASE THIS IS 'NEW' CASH 4) Then we divide the total number of shares (old and newly created) to get its per-share price. When people say 'An IPO priced at...' this is what they're referring to ... If you were using P/E or any other 'Equity Value-based multiple' for the multiple in step #2 here, then you would get to Equity Value instead and then subtract the IPO proceeds from there. ",
      "question" : "Question 2: Walk me through an IPO valuation for a company that's about to go public."
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "The formula to calendarize financial statements is as follows: TTM = Most Recent Fiscal Year + New Partial Period - Old Partial Period ... So in the example above, we would take the company's Q1 numbers, add the most recent fiscal year's numbers, and then subtract the Q1 numbers from that most recent fiscal year. For US companies, you can find these quarterly numbers in the 10-Q; for international companies they're in the 'interim' reports.",
      "question" : "Question 3: I’m looking at financial data for a public company comparable, and it’s April (Q2) right now. Walk me through how you would “calendarize” this company’s financial statements to show the Trailing Twelve Months as opposed to just the last Fiscal Year."
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "The purpose of this analusis is to look at similar transactions and see the premiums that buyers have paid to sellers' share prices when acquiring them. For example, if a company is trading at $10.00/share and the buyer acquires it for $15.00/share, that's a 50% premium. 1) First, select the precedent transactions based on industry, date (past 2-3 years for example), and size (example: over $1b market cap) 2) For each transaction, get the seller's share price 1 day, 20 days, and 60 days before the transactions was announced (you can also look at even longer intervals) 3) Then, calculate the 1-day premium, 20-day premium, etc. by dividing the per share purchase price by the appropriate share price on each day 4) Get the medians for each set, and then apply them to your company's current share price, share price 20 days ago, etc. to estimate how much of a premium the buy might pay for it. Note that you can only use this analysis when valuing public companies because private companies don't have share prices. Sometimes the set of companies here is exactly the same as your set of precedent transactions but typically it is broader.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Walk me through an M&A premiums analysis."
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "The purpose of this analysis is to project what a company's share price might be 1 or 2 years from now and then discount it back to its present value. 1) Get the median historical (usually TTM) P/E of your public company comparables 2) Apply this P/E multiple to your company's 1 year-forward or 2-year forward projected EPS to get its implied future share price 3) Then, discount this back to its present value by using a discounted rate in-line with the company's Cost of Equity figures ... You normally look at a range of P/E multiples as well as a range of discount rates for this type of analysis, and make a sensitivity table with these as inputs.",
      "question" : "Question 5: Walk me through a future share price analysis."
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "1) All the sellers in the M&A premium analysis must be public 2) Usually we use a broader set of transactions for M&A premiums - we might use fewer than 10 precendent transactions but we might have dozens of M&A premiums. The industry and financial screens are usually less stringent 3) Aside from those, the screening criteria is similar - financial, industry, geography and date",
      "question" : "Question 6: Both M&A premiums analysis and precedent transactions involve looking at previous M&A transactions. What’s the difference in how we select them?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "In a Sum-of-the-Parts analysis, you value each division of a company using separate comparables and transactions, get to reparate multiples, and then add up each division's value to get the total for the company. Example: We have a manufacturing division with $100m EBITDA, an entertainment division with $50m EBITDA and a consumer goods division with $75m EBITDA. We've selected comparable companies and transactions for each division, and the median multiple come out to 5x EBITDA for manufacturing, 8x EBITDA for entertainment, and 4x EBITDA for consumer goods. Our calculation would be 100*5 + 50*8 + 75*4 = 1.2b for the company's total value.",
      "question" : "Question 7: Walk me through a Sum-of-the-Parts analysis."
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "You value NOLs based on how much they'll save the company in taxes in future years, and then take the present value of teh sum of tax savings in future years. Two ways to assess the tax savings in future years: 1) Assume that a company can use its NOLs to completely offset its taxable income until the NOLs run out 2) In an acquisition scenario, use Section 382 and multiply the adjust long-term rate by the equity purchase price of the seller to determine the maximum allowed NOL usage in each year - and then the seller to determine the maximum allowed NOL usage in each year - and then use that to figure out the offset to taxable income ... You mightlook at NOLs in a valuation but you rarely add them in - if you did, they would be similar to cash and you would subtract NOLs to go from Equity Value to Enterprise Value, and vice versa.",
      "question" : "Question 8: How do you value Net Operating Losses and take them into account in a valuation?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "This varies by bank and group, but two common methods: 1) You pick the report with the most detailed information 2) You pick the report with numbers in the middle of the range ... Note that you do not pick reports based on which bank they're coming from. So if you're at Goldman Sachs, you would not pick all Goldman Sachs equity research - in fact that would be bad because then your valuation would not be objective.",
      "question" : "Question 9: I have a set of public company comparables and need to get the projections from equity research. How do I select which report to use?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "1) Search online and see if you can find press releases or articles in the financial press with these numbers 2) Failing that, look in equity research for the buyer around the time of the transaction and see if any of the analysts estimate the seller's numbers 3) Also look on online sources like Capital IQ and Factset and see if any of them disclose numbers or give estimates",
      "question" : "Question 10: I have a set of precedent transactions but I’m missing information like EBITDA for a lot of the companies – how can I find it if it’s not available via public sources?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "Usually you look at the TTM (Trailing Twelve Months) period for both sets, and then you look forward either 1 or 2 years. You're more likely to look backward more than 1 year and go forward more than 2 years for public company comparables; for precedent transactions it's odd to go forward more than 1 year because your information is more limited.",
      "question" : "Question 11: How far back and forward do we usually go for public company comparable and precedent transaction multiples?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "There's no 'rule' that says that is wrong or not allowed, but it can be misleading to compare companies with dramatically different margins. Due to basic arithmetic, the 40% margin company will usually have a lower multiple - whether or not its actual value is lower. In this situation, we might consider screening based on marings and remove the outliers - you would never try to 'normalize' the EBITDA multiples based on margins.",
      "question" : "Question 12: I have one company with a 40% EBITDA margin trading at 8x EBITDA, and another company with a 10% EBITDA margin trading at 16x EBITDA. What’s the problem with comparing these two valuations directly?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "You use the same methodologies, except: 1) You look at indistry-specific multiples like P/MCFE and P/NAV in addition to the more standard ones 2) You need to project the prices of commodities like oil and natural gas, and also the company's reserves to determine its revenue and cash flows in future years 3) Rather than a DCF, you use a NAV (Net Asset Value) model - it's similar but everything flows from the company's reserves rather than simple revenue growth/EBITDA margin projections ... In addition to all of the above, there are also some accounting complications with energy companies and you need to think about what a 'proven' reserve is vs. what is more speculative.",
      "question" : "Question 13: Walk me through how we might value an oil & gas company and how it’s different from a “standard” company."
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "Similar to energy, real estate is asset-intensive and a company's value depends on how much cash flow specific properties generate: 1) You look at Price/FFO, Price/AFFO (Funds from Operations), which add back Depreciation and subtract gains on property sales; NAV (Net Asset Value) is also important 2) You value properties by dividing Net Operating Income (NOI) (Property's Gross Income - Operating Expenses) by the capitaliztion rate (based on market data) 3) Replacement Valuation is more common because you can actually estimate the cost of buying new land and building new properties 4) A DCF is still a DCF, but it flows from specific properties and it might be useless depending on what kind of company you're valuing.",
      "question" : "Question 14: Walk me through how we would value a REIT (Real Estate Investment Trust) and how it differs from a “normal” company."
    }
  },
  "dcf" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "'A DCF values a company based on teh Present Value of its Cash Flows and the Net Present Value of its Terminal Value' First, you project out a company's financials using assumptions for revenue growth, expenses and Working Capital; then you get down to Free Cash Flow for each year which you then sum up and discount to a Net Present Value, based on your discount rate - usually the Weighted Average Cost of Capital. Once you have the present value of the Cash Flows, you determine the company's Terminal Value, using either the Multiples Method or the Gordon Growth Method, and then discount that back to its Net Present Value using WACC. Finally, you add the two together to determine the company's Enterprise Value.",
      "question" : "Question 1: Walk me through a DCF."
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "Subtract COGS and Operating Expenses to get to Operating Income (EBIT). Then you multiply by (1-Tax Rate), add back Depreciation and other non-cash charges, and subtract Capital Expenditures and the change in Working Capital. This gets you to unlevered FCF since you went off EBIT rather than EBT. You might want to confirm that this is what the interviewer is looking for.",
      "question" : "Question 2: Walk me through how you get from Revenue to Free Cash Flow in the projections."
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Take Cash Flow from Operations and subtract CapEx - that gets you to Leverd Cash Flow.To get to Unlevered Cash Flow, you then need to add back the tax-adjust Interest Expense and subtract the tax-adjusted Interest Income.",
      "question" : "Question 3: What’s an alternate way to calculate Free Cash Flow aside from taking Net Income, adding back Depreciation, and subtracting Changes in Operating Assets / Liabilities and CapEx?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "That's usually about as far as you can reasonably predict into the future. Less than 5 years would be too short to be useful, and over 10 years is too difficult to predict for most companies.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Why do you use 5 or 10 years for DCF projections?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "Normally you use WACC (Weighted Average Cost of Capital) though you might also use Cost of Equity depending on how you've set up the DCF.",
      "question" : "Question 5: What do you usually use for the discount rate?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "The formula is: Cost of Equity * (% Equity) + Cost of Debt * (% Debt)*(1 - Tax Rate) + Cost of Preferred * (% Preferred) ... In all cases, the percentages refer to how much of the company's capital structure is taken up by each component. For Cost of Equity, you can use the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) and for others you usually look at comparable companies/debt issuances and the interest rates and yields issued by similar companies to get estimates.",
      "question" : "Question 6: How do you calculate WACC?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "Cost of Equity = Risk-Free Rate + (Beta * Equity Risk Premium) The risk-free rate represents how much a 10-year or 20 year US Treasury should yield; Beta is calculated based on the 'riskiness' of Comparable Companies and the Equity Risk Premium is the % by which stocks are expected to out-perform risk-less assets. Normally you pull the Equity Risk Premium from a publication called Ibbotson's. Note:This formula does not tell the whole story. Depending on the bank and how precise you want to be, you could also add in a 'size premium' and 'industry premium' to account for how much a company is expected to out-perform its peers is according to its market cap or industry. Small company stocks are expected to out-perform large company stocks and certain industries are expected to out-perform others, and these premiums reflect these expectations.",
      "question" : "Question 7: How do you calculate the Cost of Equity?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "You look up the Beta for each Comparable Company (usually on Bloomberg), un-lever each one, take the median of the set and then lever it based on your company's capital structure. Then you use this Levered Beta in the Cost of Equity calculation. Unlevered Beta = Levered Beta/(1+((1 - Tax Rate) * (Total Debt/Equity))) and rearrange formula to get Levered Beta",
      "question" : "Question 8: How do you get to Beta in the Cost of Equity calculation?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "Again, keep in mind our 'apples-to-apples' theme. When you look up the Betas on Bloomberg (or whatever source you're using) they will be leverd to reflect the debt already assumed by each company. But each company's capital structure is different and we want to look at how 'risky' a company is regardless of what % debt or equity it has. To get that, we need to un-lever Beta each time. But at the end of the calculation, we need to re-lever it because we want the Beta used in Cost of Equity to reflect the true risk of our company, taking into account its capital structure this time.",
      "question" : "Question 9: Why do you have to un-lever and re-lever Beta?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "A technology company, because technology is viewed as a 'riskier' industry than manufacturing.",
      "question" : "Question 10: Would you expect a manufacturing company or a technology company to have a higher Beta?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "Levered Free Cash Flow gives you the Equity Value rather than the Enterprise Value, since the cash flow is only available to Equity Investors (debt investors have already been 'paid' with the interest payments).",
      "question" : "Question 11: Let’s say that you use Levered Free Cash Flow rather than Unlevered Free Cash Flow in your DCF – what is the effect?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "You would use Cost of Equity rather than WACC since we're not concerned with Debt or Preferred Stock in this case - we're calculating Equity Value, not Enterprise Value.",
      "question" : "Question 12: If you use Levered Free Cash Flow, what should you use as the Discount Rate? "
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "You can either apply an exit multiple to the company's Year 5 EBITDA, EBIT or FCF (Multiples Method) or you can use the Gordon Growth method to estimate its value based on its growth rate into perpetuity. The formula for TV using Gordon Growth is: TM = Year 5 FCF * (1 + Growth Rate)/(Discount Rate - Growth Rate)",
      "question" : "Question 13: How do you calculate the Terminal Value?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "In banking, you almost always use the Multiples Method to calculate Terminal Value in a DCF. It's much easier to get appropriate data for exit multiples since they are based on Comparable Companies- picking a long-term growth rate, by contrast, is always a shot in the dark. However, you might use Gordon Growth if you have no good Comparable Companies or if you have reason to believe that multiples will change significantly in teh industry several years down the road. For example, if an industry is very cyclical, you might be better off using long-term growth rates rather than exit multiples.",
      "question" : "Question 14: Why would you use Gordon Growth rather than the Multiples Method to calculate the Terminal Value?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "Normally you would use the country's long-term GDP growth rate, the rate of inflation, or something similarly conservative. For companies in mature economies, a long-term growth rate over 5% would be quite aggressive since most developed economies are growing at less than 5% per year.",
      "question" : "Question 15: What’s an appropriate growth rate to use when calculating the Terminal Value?"
    },
    "16" : {
      "answer" : "Normally you look at the Comparable Companies and pick the median of the set, or something close to it. As with anything else in finance, you always show a range of exit multiples and what the Terminal Value looks like over that range rather than picking on specific number. So if the median EBITDA multiple of the set were 8x, you might show a range of values using multiples from 6x to 10px.",
      "question" : "Question 16: How do you select the appropriate exit multiple when calculating Terminal Value?"
    },
    "17" : {
      "answer" : "It's hard to generalize because both are highly dependent on the assumptions you make. In general, the Multiples Method will be more VARIABLE than the Gordon Growth method because exit multiples tend to span a wider range than possible long-term growth rates.",
      "question" : "Question 17: Which method of calculating Terminal Value will give you a higher valuation?"
    },
    "18" : {
      "answer" : "The median multiples may change greatly in the next 5-10 years so it may no longer be accurate by the end of the period you're looking at. This is why you normally look at a wide range of multiples and do a sensitivity table to see how the valuation changes over that range. This method is particularly problematic with cyclical industries (eg. semiconductors).",
      "question" : "Question 18: What’s the flaw with basing terminal multiples on what public company comparables are trading at?"
    },
    "19" : {
      "answer" : "The 'standard' answer: if significantly more than 50% of the company's Enterprise Value comes from its TV, your DCF is probably too dependent on future assumptions. In reality, almost all DCFs are 'too dependent on future assumptions' - it's actually quite rare to see a case where the TV is LESS than 50% of the Enterprise Value. But when it gets to be in the 80-90% range, you know that you may need to re-think your assumptions...",
      "question" : "Question 19: How do you know if your DCF is too dependent on future assumptions?"
    },
    "20" : {
      "answer" : "It should be higher for the $500m company, because all else being equal, smaller companies are expected to outperform large companies in the stock market (and therefore be more 'risky'). Using a Size Premium in your calculation would also ensure that Cost of Equity is higher for the $500m company.",
      "question" : "Question 20: Should Cost of Equity be higher for a $5 billion or $500 million market cap company?"
    },
    "21" : {
      "answer" : "This is a bit of a trick question because it depends on whether or not the capital structure is the same for both companies. If the capital structure is the same in terms of percentages and interest rates and such, then WACC should be higher for the $500m company because Cost of Equity would be higher. If the capital structure is not the same, then it could go either way depending on how much debt/preferred stock each one has and what the interest rates are.",
      "question" : "Question 21: What about WACC – will it be higher for a $5 billion or $500 million company?"
    },
    "22" : {
      "answer" : "More debt means that the company is more risky, so the company's Levered Beta will be higher - all these being equal, additional debt would raise the Cost of Equity, and less debt would lower the Cost of Equity.",
      "question" : "Question 22: What’s the relationship between debt and Cost of Equity?"
    },
    "23" : {
      "answer" : "Trick-question. Dividend yields are already factored into Beta, because Beta describes returns in excess of the market as a whole - and those returns include dividends.",
      "question" : "Question 23: Cost of Equity tells us what kind of return an equity investor can expect for investing in a given company – but what about dividends? Shouldn’t we factor dividend yield into the formula?"
    },
    "24" : {
      "answer" : "There is an alternate formula: Cost of Equity = (Dividends per Share / Share Price) + Growth Rate of Dividends ... This is less common than the 'standard' formula but sometimes you use it for companies where dividends are more important or when you lack proper information on Beta and other variables that go into calculating Cost of Equity with CAPM.",
      "question" : "Question 24: How can we calculate Cost of Equity WITHOUT using CAPM?"
    },
    "25" : {
      "answer" : "Tricky question - the one without debt will have a higher WACC up to a certain point because debt is 'less expensive' than equity. Why? 1) Interest on debt is tax-deductible (hence the (1 - Tax Rate) multiplication in the WACC formula) 2) Debt is senior to equity in a company's capital structure - debt holders would be paid first in a liquidation or bankruptcy 3) Intuitively, interest rates on debt are usually lower than the Cost of Equity numbers you see (usually over 10%). As a result, the Cost of Debt portion of WACC will contribute less to the total figure than the Cost of Equity portion will. However, the above is true only to a certain point. Once a company's debt goes up high enough, the interest rate will rise dramatically to reflect teh additional risk and so the Cost of Debt would start to increase - if it gets high enough, it might become higher tahn Cost of Equity and additional debt would INCREASE WACC. It's a 'U-shape' curve where debt DECREASES WACC to a point, then starts increasing it.",
      "question" : "Question 25: Two companies are exactly the same, but one has debt and one does not – which one will have the higher WACC?"
    },
    "26" : {
      "answer" : "You should start by saying, it 'depends' but most of the time the 10% difference in revenue will have more of an impact. That change in revenue doesn't affect only the current year's revenue, but also the revenue/EBITDA far into the future and even the terminal value.",
      "question" : "Question 26: Which has a greater impact on a company’s DCF valuation – a 10% change in revenue or a 1% change in the discount rate?"
    },
    "27" : {
      "answer" : "In this case, the discount rate is likely to have a bigger impact on the valuation, though the correct answer should start with , 'It could go either way, but most of the time...'",
      "question" : "Question 27: What about a 1% change in revenue vs. a 1% change in the discount rate?"
    },
    "28" : {
      "answer" : "This is problematic because private companies don't have market caps or Betas. In this case you would most likely just estimate WACC based on work done by auditors or valuation specialists, or based on what WACC for comparable public companies is.",
      "question" : "Question 28: How do you calculate WACC for a private company?"
    },
    "29" : {
      "answer" : "You can take a few different approaches: 1) You can create your own projections 2) You can modify management's projections downward to make them more conservative 3) You can show a sensitivity table based on differnt growth rates and margins and show the values assuming managements' projections and assuming a more conservative set of numbers ... In reality, you'd probably do all of these if you had unrealistic projections.",
      "question" : "Question 29: What should you do if you don’t believe management’s projections for a DCF model?"
    },
    "30" : {
      "answer" : "Banks use debt differently than other companies and do not re-invest it in the business - they use it to create products instead. Also, interest is a critical part of bank's business models and working capital takes up a huge part of their Balance Sheets - so a DCF for a financial model would not make much sense. For financial institutions, it's more common to use a dividend discount model for valuation purposes.",
      "question" : "Question 30: Why would you not use a DCF for a bank or other financial institution?"
    },
    "31" : {
      "answer" : "Example sensitivities: 1) Revenue Growth vs. Terminal Multiple 2) EBITDA Margin vs. Terminal Multiple 3) Terminal Multiple vs. Discount Rate 4) Long-Term Growth Rate vs Discount Rate ... And any combination of these (except Terminal Multiple vs. Long-Term Growth Rate which would make no sense).",
      "question" : "Question 31: What types of sensitivity analyses would we look at in a DCF?"
    },
    "32" : {
      "answer" : "Trick question. You don't account for this at all in a DCF, because paying off debt principal shows up in Cash Flow from Financing on the Cash Flow Statement - but we only go down to Cash Flow from Operations and then subtract Capital Expenditures to get to Free Cash Flow. If we were looking at Levered Cash Flow, then our interest expense would decline in future years due to the principal being paid off - but we still wouldn't account the principal repayments themselves anywhere.",
      "question" : "Question 32: A company has a high debt load and is paying off a significant portion of its principal each year. How do you account for this in a DCF?"
    }
  },
  "adv-dcf" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "You would use it to represent the fact that a company's cash flow does not come 100% at the end of each year - instead, it comes in evenly throughout each year. In a DCF without mid-year convention, we would use discount period numbers of 1 for the first year, 2 for the second year,3 for the third year, and so on. With a mid-year convention, we would instead use 0.5 for the first year, 1.5 for the second year, 2.5 for the third year, and so on.",
      "question" : "Question 1: Explain why we would use the mid-year convention in a DCF."
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "The rule is that you divide the stub discount period by 2, and then you simply subtract 0.5 from the 'normal' discount periods for the future years.",
      "question" : "Question 2: What discount period numbers would I use for the mid-year convention if I have a stub period – e.g. Q4 of Year 1 – in my DCF?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "When you're discounting the terminal value back to the present value, you use different numbers for the discount period depending on whether you're using the Multiples Method of Gordon Growth Method: Multiples Method = You add 0.5 to the final year discount number to reflect the fact that you're assuming the company gets sold at the END of the year; Gordon Growth Method: You use the final year discount number as is, because you're assuming the cash flows grow into perpetuity and that they are still received throughout the year rather than just at the end.",
      "question" : "Question 3: How does the terminal value calculation change when we use the mid-year convention?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "Once you get to Enterprise Value, ADD cash and then subtract debt, preferred stock, and minority interest (and any other debt-like items) to get to Equity Value. Then, you need to use a circular calculation that takes into account the basic shares oustanding, options, warrants, convertibles, and other dilutive securities. It's circular because the diluation from these depends on the per-share price - but the per-share price depends on number of shares outstanding, which depends on teh per-share price. To resolve this, you need to enable iterative calculations in Excel so that it can cycle through to find an approximate per-share price.",
      "question" : "Question 4: If I’m working with a public company in a DCF, how do I calculate its per-share value?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "The mechanics are the same as a DCF, but we use dividends rather than free cash flows: 1) Project out the company’s earnings, down to earnings per share (EPS) 2) Assume a dividend payout ratio – what percentage of the EPS actually gets paid out to shareholders in the form of dividends – based on what the firm has done historically and how much regulatory capital it needs 3) Use this to calculate dividends over the next 5-10 years 4) Discount each dividend to its present value based on Cost of Equity- NOT WACC - and then sum these up 5) Calculate the terminal value based on P/E and EPS in the final year, and then discount this to its present value based on Cost of Equity 6) Sum the present value of the terminal value and the present values of the dividends to get the company's net present per-share value",
      "question" : "Question 5: Walk me through a Dividend Discount Model (DDM) that you would use in place of a normal DCF for financial institutions."
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "Trick question. If the convertible debt is in-the-money then you do not count it as debt but instead assume that it contributes to dilution, so the company's Equity Value is higher. If it's out-of-the-money then you count it as debt and use the interest rate on the convertible for Cost of Debt.",
      "question" : "Question 6: When you’re calculating WACC, let’s say that the company has convertible debt. Do you count this as debt when calculating Levered Beta for the company?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "In this scenario, you would add CapEx spending of $100 in year 4 of the DCF, which would reduce FCF for that year by $100. The Enterprise Value, in turn, would fall by the present value of that $100 decrease in FCF. The actual math here is messy but you would calculate the present value by dividing $100 by ((1 + Discount Rate) ^ 4) - the '4' just represents year 4 here. Then you would subtract this amount from the Enterprise Value.",
      "question" : "Question 7: We’re creating a DCF for a company that is planning to buy a factory for $100 in cash (no debt or other financing) in Year 4. Currently the present value of its Enterprise Value according to the DCF is $200. How would we change the DCF to account for the factory purchase, and what would our new Enterprise Value be?"
    }
  },
  "merger" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "'A merger model is used to analyze the financial profiles of 2 companies, the purchase price and how the purchase is made, and determines whether the buyer's EPS increases or decreases. Step 1 is making assumptions about the acquisition - the price and whether it was cash, stock or debt or some combination of those. Next, you determine the valuations and shares outstanding of the buyer and seller and project out an Income Statement for each one. Finally, you combine the IS, adding up line items such as Revenue and Operating Expenses, and adjusting for Foregone Interest on Cash and Interest Piad on Debt in the Combined Pre-Tax Income line;you apply the buyer's Tax Rate to get the Combined Net Income, and then divide by the new share count to determine the combined EPS.",
      "question" : "Question 1: Walk me through a basic merger model."
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "There's always a buyer and a seller in any M&A deal - the difference between 'merger' and 'acquisition' is more semantic than anything. In a merger, the companies are close to the same size, whereas in an acquisition the buyer is significantly larger.",
      "question" : "Question 2: What’s the difference between a merger and an acquisition?"
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "Several possible reasons: 1) The buyer wants to gain market share by buying a competitor 2) The buyer needs to grow more quickly and sees an acquisition as a way to do that 3) The buyer believes the seller is undervalued 4) The buyer wants to acquire the seller's customers so it can up-sell and cross-sell to them 5) The buyer thinks the seller has a critical technology, intellectual property or some other 'secrete sauce' it can use to significantly enhance its business 6) The buyer believes it can achieve significant synergies and therefore make the deal accretive for its shareholders",
      "question" : "Question 3: Why would a company want to acquire another company?"
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "An acquisition is dilutive if the additional amount of Net Income the seller contributes is not enough to offset the buyer's foregone interest on cash, additional interest paid on debt, and the effects of issuing additional shares. Acquisition effects - such as amortization of intangibles - can also make an acquisition dilutive.",
      "question" : "Question 4: Why would an acquisition be dilutive?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "If the deal involves just cash and debt, you can sum up the interest expense for debt and the foregone interest on cash, then compare it against the seller's Pre-Tax Income. If it's an all stock deal you can use a shortcut to assess whether it is accretive (see question 7). But if the deal involves cash, stock, and debt, there's no quick rule-of-thumb you can use unless you're lightning fast with mental math.",
      "question" : "Question 5: Is there a rule of thumb for calculating whether an acquisition will be accretive or dilutive?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "Trick question. You can't tell unless you ALSO know it is an all-stock deal. If it's an all-cash or all-debt deal, the P/E multiples of the buyer and seller don't matter because no stock is being issued. Sure, generally getting more earnings for less is good and is more likely to be accretive but there's no hard-and-fast rule unless it's an all-stock deal.",
      "question" : "Question 6: A company with a higher P/E acquires one with a lower P/E – is this accretive or dilutive?"
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "In an all-stock deal, if the buyer has a higher P/E than the seller, it will be accretive; if the buyer has a lower P/E, it will be dilutive. On an intuitive level if you're paying more for earnings than what the market values your own earnings at, you can guess it will be dilutive; and likewise, if you're paying less for earnings than what the market values your own earnings at, you can guess that it would be accretive.",
      "question" : "Question 7: What is the rule of thumb for assessing whether an M&A deal will be accretive or dilutive?"
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "1) Foregone Interest on Cash - the buyer loses the interest it would have otherwise earned if it uses cash for the acquisition 2) Additional Interest on Debt - the buyer pays additional interest expense if it uses debt 3) Additional Shares Outstanding - if the buyer pays with stick, it must issue additional shares 4) Combined Financial Statements - after the acquisition, the seller's financials are added to the buyer's 5) Creation of Goodwill & Other Intangibles - these balance sheet items that represent a 'premium' paid to a company's 'fair value' also get created ... There's actually more than this (see advanced questions), but this is usually sufficient to mention in interviews.",
      "question" : "Question 8: What are the complete effects of an acquisition?"
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "It might be saving its cash for something else or it might be concerned about running low if business takes a turn for the worst; its stock may also be trading at an all-time high and it might be eager to use that instead (in finance terms this would be 'more expensive' but a lot of executives value having a safety cushion in the form of a large cash balance).",
      "question" : "Question 9: If a company were capable of paying 100% in cash for another company, why would it choose NOT to do so?"
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "Because the strategic acquirer can realize revenue and cost synergies that the private equity firm cannot unless it combines the company with a complementary portfolio company. Those synergies boost the effective valuation for the target company.",
      "question" : "Question 10: Why would a strategic acquirer typically be willing to pay more for a company than a private equity firm would?"
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "These represent the value over the 'fair market value' of the seller that the buyer has paid. You calculate the number by subtracting the book value of a company from its equity purchase price. More specifically, Goodwill and Other Intangibles represent things like the value of customer relationships, brand names and intellectual property – valuable, but not true financial Assets that show up on the Balance Sheet.",
      "question" : "Question 11: Why do Goodwill & Other Intangibles get created in an acquisition?"
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "Goodwill typically stays the same over many years and is not amortized. It changes only if there’s goodwill impairment (or another acquisition). Other Intangible Assets, by contrast, are amortized over several years and affect the Income Statement by hitting the Pre-Tax Income line. There’s also a difference in terms of what they each represent, but bankers rarely go into that level of detail – accountants and valuation specialists worry about assigning each one to specific items.",
      "question" : "Question 12: What is the difference between Goodwill and Other Intangible Assets?"
    },
    "13" : {
      "answer" : "Yes. You could also have a Purchased In-Process R&D Write-off and a Deferred Revenue Write-off. The first refers to any Research & Development projects that were purchased in the acquisition but which have not been completed yet. The logic is that unfinished R&D projects require significant resources to complete, and as such, the 'expense' must be recognized as part of the acquisition. The second refers to cases where the seller has collected cash for a service but not yet recorded it as revenue, and the buyer must write-down the value of the Deferred Revenue to avoid 'double-counting' revenue.",
      "question" : "Question 13: Is there anything else 'intangible' besides Goodwill & Other Intangibles that could also impact the combined company?"
    },
    "14" : {
      "answer" : "Synergies refer to cases where 2 + 2 = 5 (or 6, or 7...) in an acquisition. Basically, the buyer gets more value than out of an acquisition than what the financials would predict. There are 2 types: Revenue Synergies: The combined company can cross-sell products to new customers or up-sell new products to existing customers. It might also be able to expand into new geographies as a result of the deal; Cost Synergies: The combined company can consolidate buildings and administrative staff and can lay off redundant employees. It might also be able to shut down redundant stores or locations.",
      "question" : "Question 14: What are synergies, and can you provide a few examples?"
    },
    "15" : {
      "answer" : "Revenue Synergies: Normally you add these to the Revenue figure for the combined company and then assume a certain margin on the Revenue – this additional Revenue then flows through the rest of the combined Income Statement ... Cost Synergies: Normally you reduce the combined COGS or Operating Expenses by this amount, which in turn boosts the combined Pre-Tax Income and thus Net Income, raising the EPS and making the deal more accretive.",
      "question" : "Question 15: How are synergies used in merger models?"
    },
    "16" : {
      "answer" : "No one in M&A takes revenue synergies seriously because they’re so hard to predict. Cost synergies are taken a bit more seriously because it’s more straightforward to see how buildings and locations might be consolidated and how many redundant employees might be eliminated. That said, the chances of any synergies actually being realized are almost 0 so few take them seriously at all.",
      "question" : "Question 16: Are revenue or cost synergies more important?"
    },
    "17" : {
      "answer" : "Assuming the buyer had unlimited resources, it would always prefer to use cash when buying another company. Why? 1) Cash is 'cheaper' than debt because interest rates on cash are usually under 5% whereas debt interest rates are almost always higher than that. Thus, foregone interest on cash is almost always less than additional interest paid on debt for the same amount of cash/debt 2) Cash is also less 'risky' than debt because there’s no chance the buyer might fail to raise sufficient funds from investors 3) It’s hard to compare the “cost” directly to stock, but in general stock is the most 'expensive' way to finance a transaction – remember how the Cost of Equity is almost always higher than the Cost of Debt? That same principle applies here 3) Cash is also less risky than stock because the buyer’s share price could change dramatically once the acquisition is announced.",
      "question" : "Question 17: All else being equal, which method would a company prefer to use when acquiring another company – cash, stock, or debt?"
    },
    "18" : {
      "answer" : "Generally you would look at Comparable Companies/Precedent Transactions to determine this. You would use the combined company's LTM (Last Twelve Months) EBITDA figure, find the median Debt/EBITDA ratio of whatever companies you're looking at, and apply that to your own EBITDA figure to get a rough idea of how much debt you could raise. You would also look at 'Debt Comps' for companies in the same industry and see what types of debt and how many tranches they have used.",
      "question" : "Question 18: How much debt could a company issue in a merger or acquisition?"
    },
    "19" : {
      "answer" : "You use the same Valuation methodologies we already discussed. If the sller is a public company, you would pay more attention to the premium paid over the current share price to make sure it's 'sufficient' (generally in the 15-30% range) to win shareholder approval. For private sellers, more weight is placed on the traditional methodologies.",
      "question" : "Question 19: How do you determine the Purchase Price for the target company in an acquisition?"
    },
    "20" : {
      "answer" : "There would be an incredibly high amount of Goodwill and Other Intangibles created if the price is far above the fair market value of the company. Depending on how the acquisition goes, there might be a large goodwill impairment damage charge later on if the company decides it overpaid. A recent example is the eBay/Skype deal, in which eBay paid a huge premium and extremely high multiple for Skype. It created excess Goodwill and Other Intangibles, and eBay later ended up writing down much of the value and taking a large quaterly loss as a result.",
      "question" : "Question 20: Let’s say a company overpays for another company – what typically happens afterwards and can you give any recent examples?"
    },
    "21" : {
      "answer" : "The buyer’s share price would fall by whatever per-share dollar amount corresponds to the $50 million loss in value. Note that it would not necessarily be cut in half. Depending on how the deal was structured, the seller would effectively only be receiving half of what it had originally negotiated. This illustrates one of the major risks of all-stock deals: sudden changes in share price could dramatically impact valuation.",
      "question" : "Question 21: A buyer pays $100 million for the seller in an all-stock deal, but a day later the market decides it’s only worth $50 million. What happens?"
    },
    "22" : {
      "answer" : "Like so many things, M&A is 'easier said than done'. In practice, it's very difficult to acquire and integrate a different company, actually realize synergies and also turn the acquired company into a profitable division. Many deals are also done for the wrong reason, such as CEOs ego or pressure from shareholders. Any deal done without both parties' best interests in mind is likely to fail.",
      "question" : "Question 22: Why do most mergers and acquisitions fail?"
    },
    "23" : {
      "answer" : "The model is used as a sanity check and is used to test various assumptions. A company would NEVER decide to do a deal based on the output of a model. It might say, 'Ok the model tell us this deal could work and be moderately accretive - it's worth exploring more'. It would never say 'Aga! This model predicts 21% accretion - we should definitely acquire them now!' Emotions, ego and personalities play a far bigger role in M&A (and any type of negotiations) than numbers do.",
      "question" : "Question 23: What role does a merger model play in deal negotiations?"
    },
    "24" : {
      "answer" : "The most common variables to look at are Purchase Price, % Stock/Cash/Debt, Revenue Synergies, Expense Synergies. Sometimes you also look at different operative sensitivities like Revenue Growth or EBITDA Margin, but it's more common to build these into your model as different scenarios instead. You might look at sensitivity tables showing the EPS accretion/dilution at different ranges for the Purchase Price vs Cost Synergies, Purchase Price vs Revenue Synergies, or Purchase Price vs % Cash (and so on).",
      "question" : "Question 24: What types of sensitivities would you look at in a merger model? What variables would you look at?"
    }
  },
  "adv-merger" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "In purchase accounting the seller’s shareholders’ equity number is wiped out and the premium paid over that value is recorded as Goodwill on the combined balance sheet post-acquisition. In pooling accounting, you simply combine the 2 shareholders’ equity numbers rather than worrying about Goodwill and the related items that get created. There are specific requirements for using pooling accounting, so in 99% of M&A deals you will use purchase accounting.",
      "question" : "Question 1: What’s the difference between Purchase Accounting and Pooling Accounting in an M&A deal?"
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "'Let’s say that Microsoft is going to acquire Yahoo. Yahoo makes money from search advertising online, and they make a certain amount of revenue per search (RPS). Let’s say this RPS is $0.10 right now. If Microsoft acquired it, we might assume that they could boost this RPS by $0.01 or $0.02 because of their superior monetization. So to calculate the additional revenue from this synergy, we would multiply this $0.01 or $0.02 by Yahoo’s total # of searches, get the total additional revenue, and then select a margin on it to determine how much flows through to the combined company’s Operating Income.'",
      "question" : "Question 2: Walk me through a concrete example of how to calculate revenue synergies."
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "'Let’s say that Microsoft still wants to acquire Yahoo!. Microsoft has 5,000 SG&A-related employees, whereas Yahoo has around 1,000. Microsoft calculates that post-transaction, it will only need about 200 of Yahoo’s SG&A employees, and its existing employees can take over the rest of the work. To calculate the Operating Expenses the combined company would save, we would multiply these 800 employees Microsoft is going to fire post-transaction by their average salary.'",
      "question" : "Question 3: Walk me through an example of how to calculate expense synergies."
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "You apply Section 382 to determine how much of the seller’s NOLs are usable each year. Allowable NOLs = Equity Purchase Price * Highest of Past 3 Months’ Adjusted Long Term Rates So if our equity purchase price were $1 billion and the highest adjusted long-term rate were 5%, then we could use $1 billion * 5% = $50 million of NOLs each year. If the seller had $250 million in NOLs, then the combined company could use $50 million of them each year for 5 years to offset its taxable income.",
      "question" : "Question 4: How do you take into account NOLs in an M&A deal?"
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "These get created when you write up assets – both tangible and intangible – and when you write down assets in a transaction. An asset write-up creates a deferred tax liability, and an asset write-down creates a deferred tax asset. You write down and write up assets because their book value – what’s on the balance sheet – often differs substantially from their 'fair market value.'' An asset write-up creates a deferred tax liability because you’ll have a higher depreciation expense on the new asset, which means you save on taxes in the short-term – but eventually you’ll have to pay them back, hence the liability. The opposite applies for an asset write-down and a deferred tax asset.",
      "question" : "Question 5: Why do deferred tax liabilities (DTLs) and deferred tax assets (DTAs) get created in M&A deals?"
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 6: "
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 7: "
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 8: "
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 9: "
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 10: "
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 11: "
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 12: "
    },
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 1: "
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 2: "
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 3: "
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 4: "
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 5: "
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 6: "
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 7: "
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 8: "
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 9: "
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 10: "
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 11: "
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 12: "
    }
  },
  "filler-template" : {
    "1" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 1: "
    },
    "2" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 2: "
    },
    "3" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 3: "
    },
    "4" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 4: "
    },
    "5" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 5: "
    },
    "6" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 6: "
    },
    "7" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 7: "
    },
    "8" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 8: "
    },
    "9" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 9: "
    },
    "10" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 10: "
    },
    "11" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 11: "
    },
    "12" : {
      "answer" : "",
      "question" : "Question 12: "
    }
  }




}
